[Music playing]
Hey, guys.
Mmm, collecting snails?
Yeah, Mr. Feeny said
we can take 'em...
off his flowers
and use them for bait...
for when we all go
fishing Sunday.
Fish don't eat snails.
Gee, I guess I was mistaken.
Well, whenever
you guys are ready...
the bass master here
is all set...
to pass on
to the younger generation...
some of the finer points
of spin casting.
Manipulating young
and impressionable minds.
I hope you're proud
of yourself, Mr. Feeny.
Indeed I am, Mr. Matthews.
Come on, guys.
Now, the main thing
to remember is...
that basically
it's a simple flick...
of the wrist.
You open the bail...
hold the line
with your finger...
and then it's 2:00, 10:00.
2:00, 10:00.
[Crash]
Kind of a quarter
after 3:00 thing...
you got going
on there, Dad, huh?
May a, uh, fellow
angler try his luck?
Be my guest, George.
Thank you. Ha ha!
That fella out there.
[Clink]
It's like getting
back on a bicycle.
one never forgets.
Mr. Feeny, you fish?
oh, sure. I'm an old
bass hog from way back.
I'll never forget that
September morn, 1956.
I was after small-mouth bass
on the Louisiana Delta.
Sounds fascinating, George.
Spanish moss
hanging down...
and the cypress knees
jutting up...
through the brackish water
of the bayou.
Sounds fascinating,
George.
Dad, how come Eric's
not coming with us this year?
Well, your brother's
discovered girls.
He can't sit still.
When you're Eric's age...
and you can't sit still,
I'll take Morgan.
It's the endless cycle
of fishing.
And what about after Morgan?
Well, then
I'll just be some guy...
in a fishing hat
with a lot of boring stories.
Did you just
scare yourself, Dad?
Whoa, yes, I think I did.
[Theme music playing]
Hi. I'm Morgan,
and this is my brother Eric.
He's very shy.
Ha ha ha. Good girl.
Eric, what are you
teaching her?
Nothing.
I get to help Eric
meet girls.
No, you don't. She doesn't.
You don't.
My brother thinks
you are so cute.
So this is why you've been
taking her to the mall.
-Well, I think it's great.
-You do?
-Mm-hmm.
-Ha ha ha.
I think it's a perfect way
for you and your sister...
to spend quality time
together.
Well, you know, some guys
use a golden retriever.
I figure, why not use
the weasel here?
[Car horn honks
"La Cucaracha"]
It's Grandma!
Hey, it's Grandma!
Yeah, it's Grandma.
oK, open up a lane.
I'm coming through.
I've been sitting on
my keister for ten hours...
in that Winnebago.
I need some stretching room.
Hey!
Grandma! Grandma!
BoTH: Where's my present?
I thought this year
maybe you'd buy me one.
Nuh-uh.
You're the grandma.
I am? oh well,
in that case--
Uh-oh, what have we here?
A dolly.
Ha ha. Well,
it's a shrunken head.
Not a real one.
They don't sell real ones
in Tijuana.
Not for a buck.
That's a cool bullwhip,
Grandma.
oh, yeah, and it's yours.
I had the wagon master
to go with it...
but he slipped out
of the cuffs in Juarez.
I know, I know.
I didn't call.
You never do, Bernice.
Well, it's not my style.
Hey, I got something
for you, too.
Yeah. Dried cactus.
It's from Albuquerque.
An old Navajo tradition.
Keeps you regular
as a diesel.
Thanks for preparing us
for middle age, Mom.
We'll think of you...
several times a day.
So, what brings you
to our neck of the woods?
Did your convoy swing through?
Yeah, yeah.
We made a killing
in bingo country...
so now we're heading out
to Palm Springs...
to buy ourselves
some new butts. Ha ha ha!
Grandma!
Kiddo!
Finally decided
to show your face, huh?
What'd they do,
let you out of detention early?
Yeah, well,
I heard "La Cucaracha"...
from all the way
down at the park.
How long are you staying?
oh, just the weekend.
Speaking of which--
hey, you two kids...
cancel all your plans
for Saturday...
'cause, Morgan, you and l
are gonna go shopping.
We are gonna buy
so many new clothes...
you won't know
what to do with them all.
I'll wear them, then I'll
throw them on the floor.
Ha! Why not?
And then I thought we'd
take in the auto show.
I hear they got
some pretty hot babes...
sitting on the hoods
of those hotrods.
There's something
I might enjoy.
And Sunday, kiddo,
you and l...
we are gonna go get
this baseball card signed...
by the guy in the picture.
Cal Ripken?
This is Cal Ripken's
rookie card!
How'd you get this?
How'd I get it?
I shot a man in Reno
just to watch him die...
and then I pried that
out of his cold, dead fingers.
or I bought it for seven bucks
at a swap meet.
You make the call.
And we're gonna
get him to sign it?
Well, would you like that?
What are you, new?
-Hey!
oh, man, that was
the best auto show ever.
They had Bernie Koppell
and Jamie Farr...
right up there
on the same stage.
Where else you gonna get that?
Hey, Cor, check it out.
I had the Lamborghini girl
sign my arm.
Lamborghini girl?
Eric, how can you
even compare...
the Lamborghini girl
to Cal Ripken?
Has the Lamborghini girl
played 1,900 straight games?
No, but has
Cal Ripken ever posed...
For the Victoria's Secret
catalogue?
Eric, I feel
we're growing apart.
Told her maybe we could take
a drive once I get my license.
She laughed,
but it was a flirty laugh.
Graziella Terziana.
I think she's French.
Boy, I'm bushed.
What, with chasing your sister
in and out of dressing rooms...
and chasing your brother away...
from those bikini models'
dressing rooms...
these dogs are barking.
You're not too tired
for tomorrow, are you?
Are you kidding?
You and me?
I wouldn't miss that
for the world.
Mr. Matthews,
just the man I wanted to see.
-Mr. Feeny?
-Let me ask you--
if one were entertaining
a young woman...
a young girl your age...
um, how would he
go about it?
Mr. Feeny,
you dating a teenage girl?
Not since
the Eisenhower administration.
No. My niece is visiting
for a few days.
She's your age.
She'll need to be entertained...
And I thought that maybe
you could help me out.
Look, I'd love to meet
your niece, Mr. Feeny,
But, see, I got this really bad
case of strep throat.
It's spreading down my lungs
and into my pancreas...
so, as you can see,
I'm--I'm completely strep.
Relax.
I'm merely curious...
as to how a contemporary
teenage girl entertains herself.
oh, oK. Well,
it's my experience...
that if they can't find
a senior with a car...
they'll settle for
some gullible sophomore...
who's willing
to empty his pockets...
on a dinner
he can't really afford...
a movie
he doesn't want to see...
and a door
slammed in his face.
Somewhere in that
brimming cup of bile...
I heard dinner and a movie.
Yeah, see,
dinner and a movie...
is the premier form
of dating entertainment.
Dinner, movie. Movie, dinner.
Dinner, dinner, movie, movie.
A wonderfully rich tapestry
of human experience.
Don't mock what I am,
Mr. Feeny.
Mom, where's Grandma?
We were supposed
to leave ten minutes ago...
and her Winnebago's
not even outside.
You know what, Cor?
I was gonna bake
some blueberry muffins.
You want to help me?
-Bake?
-Mm-hmm.
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
There's nothing
I'd rather do more.
oh, wait. I'm lying.
I'd rather go to Baltimore.
Well, how about just
until you leave?
ohh...so how long
do you think...
I could go
without taking a shower...
before my arm gets
all gross disgusting?
Is this what's gonna happen
to me when my hormones kick in?
Yeah, like I don't have anything
else on my mind but girls.
Look, I got a lot of other
things on my mind besides girls.
A lot of other things.
There's, like--
Girl! Girl! Right there!
Right there!
Where?
It's Feeny's niece.
She's unbelievable.
I--I gotta think.
I gotta think.
I got to take her to a world
she's never been to before.
Dinner. Movie.
Movie. Dinner.
This has to be perfectly
orchestrated, or else--
Weasel!
oK, weasel, do you remember
what we've been practicing?
This is my brother Eric.
He's very shy.
Ha ha.
Perfect. Look,
in exactly one minute...
I want you to come outside...
and do what we've been doing
at the mall.
How will I know
when it's a minute?
oK? Minute, ding.
Minute, ding.
Movie, dinner.
How you doing, Mr. Feeny?
How could I help you
in the garden today?
oh.
oh, hi. I'm Eric.
I'm Jessica.
Strep throat cleared up,
did it, Mr. Matthews?
Strep throat?
A guy like me?
No. See, I work out
much too hard...
to ever get strep throat.
So, uh, where would you
like me to move...
this enormously heavy bag
of fertilizer?
I hadn't planned
on moving it at all.
Let me just effortlessly
toss it over here, then.
Hoo-dah!
[Bell dings]
This is my brother Eric.
He's very shy.
Speaking of fertilizer.
Is this your little sister?
That she is.
I love Eric.
oh, please. Jessica...
you couldn't possibly fall
for this line of--
She is so cute.
And so well-rehearsed.
Eric's taking me
to the carnival today.
When did I say that?
Ha ha. Looks like your parrot
has learned a few new words.
Do you want to come with us?
oh, with us.
To the carnival with us, yes.
Please come With us.
Well, if that's oK with you,
Uncle George.
Well, I think
the polite thing...
would be to extend an invitation
for me to join you.
Mr. Feeny, would you like
to come to the carnival with us?
oh, thank you so very
much for asking...
but no. I'd rather
have gum surgery.
oK, now, remember
to take those out...
in a couple minutes
so they don't stick.
Mom, I kind of got the hang
of it in the last four batches.
Is Grandma lost or What?
I don't know, Cor,
but, hey...
you know what?
I was gonna bake a cake next.
You want to help me out?
Look, Mom, I know
you're trying to do this...
to distract me and all...
but what if something
happened to Grandma?
Maybe we should call
the police.
-No, I don't think so.
-Why not?
Because I'm sure
that she's fine.
Then why isn't she here yet?
Honey, I've known
your grandmother...
for a long time,
and there's something...
you need to understand
about her.
I understand that
if Grandma's not here yet...
she must have
a very good reason.
She's not coming, is she?
I'm sorry, Cory.
I knowthis is disappointing.
Eh, it was just
a stupid road trip.
I mean, what kind of city
is Baltimore, anyway?
An American League city.
Hey, why don't you call Shawn?
See if he wants to go bowling.
-Cool. I'll drive.
-or I'll drive.
That could work, too.
I'll call my best bud Shawn...
the one guy I can count on
to be there.
Hi, Mrs. Hunter?
It's Cory. Shawn around?
What do you mean,
he's gone fishing?
Did you know your husband's
cheating on me...
with someone else's son?
You forgot to call Shawn.
Good-bye, Mrs. Hunter.
I forgot.
You didn't tell him you weren't
going on the fishing trip?
I forgot.
So he still showed up.
I guess he didn't forget.
Now he's out there
with my dad...
drinking root beer,
eating potato chips...
bonding away.
I miss one thing
with my dad...
and he drops me
for the first available son.
Where are you going?
I'll be in the tree house.
Hold my calls.
MORGAN: Eric is the best
brother in the whoLe worLd.
That's enough, Morgan.
That was so sweet of you to play
four hours of skeeball...
just to win her that giraffe.
3,000 tickets.
Eric's gonna give me
his new sunglasses.
No, he's not.
You know, you can really
tell a lot about a guy...
by the way
he treats his sister.
oh, you mean these.
There you go.
Eric is such
a good-looking boy.
Yeah, thanks.
Are we all done for the day?
Yes, we're done. Bye-bye.
She's adorable.
She's not the only one.
Who's Graziella Terziana?
What?
Her name,
it's written on your arm.
Uh, that--
I can't stop every girl
who wants to sign my body.
oh, Mr. Charming.
I could loan you a pen.
And smart, too,
Using his little sister
as date bait like that.
That obvious, huh?
oh, yeah. Heh.
Big mistake?
Did I say that?
So I didn't have
to work so hard.
Who said you had
to work at all?
Nice night, huh?
Yeah.
Well, we're just,
uh, passing through.
Good. Pass.
Eric, the lipmaster.
Yeah. Sure.
Look, anybody else,
or are we all done here?
Everyone have
a great day without me?
How long have you
been up there?
Long enough to watch you
swap spit with a Feeny.
Well, I'd say the mood
is sufficiently killed...
wouldn't you?
Dead and buried.
I think my little sister's
busy tomorrow...
so it looks like
it's just you and me.
I'll bring the pen.
Good night.
Everyone. Ha ha.
She's related to Feeny?
Niece.
Nice.
Nice? She's beautiful.
That's the most incredible girl
I ever kissed.
Which puts her at the top
of a list of what, two?
Look, making out
is not a spectator sport.
ooh...
What are you doing back
from Baltimore so early?
-I didn't go to Baltimore.
-Why not?
'Cause I stayed here all day
'cause Grandma dumped me...
while my best friend was out
Stealing my dad.
oh, grow up.
I wasn't stealing your father.
-Good night, Shawn.
-Night, Dad.
-So Grandma never showed, huh?
-Nah, she didn't.
You want to talk about it?
Doesn't really seem like
there's much to talk about.
Hoo, boy, are you wrong.
Where are you going?
I'm hungry. Shawn ate
everything on the boat...
except the worms.
He usually likes those.
Uh, I can highly recommend
the muffins.
These are a little dry.
Great. I cook and I slave,
and this is the thanks I get.
You made these?
I didn't have
anything else to do...
'cause Grandma
didn't show up.
I've been there.
Wait a minute.
She did this to you?
Hey, pick a category.
You like sports?
Birthdays?
You like rocket ships?
I'll take rocket ships.
All right. Um...
one day my class...
was supposed to go
on this field trip
to the Franklin
Museum of Science...
to see
the "Man in Space" exhibit.
Cool.
Yeah, it would've been, except
that Grandma forgot to return...
the permission slip,
so I didn't get to go.
I been there.
Yeah, me, too, and I felt
just the way you're feeling now.
-Did you hate her?
-Well, no.
It's kind of hard
to hate her, Cory...
'cause a couple months later,
she woke me up...
in the middle of the night,
she bundles me up...
throws me in the Winnebago...
we drive for two days
and two nights.
Where'd she take you?
Cape Canaveral.
Mercury 3.
First American in space.
My classmates
are back in Philadelphia...
Looking at it on a little
black-and-white TV.
I'm there feeling the heat
from the rocket on my face.
Grandma took you all the way
to Cape Canaveral?
See, Grandma doesn't show love
like other people do...
but she loves you
no matter what you think.
She just shows love
in her own way.
And when she's with you,
she wants it to be so special...
that you'll always remember.
I always do remember.
Yeah, so do l.
When that rocket took off...
and the smile on my face
was a mile wide...
and all of America was
watching their little TV set...
I remember that my mother
was watching me.
[Car horn honks
"La Cucaracha"]
Guess who.
Hi, Mom.
Hi, Alan.
You'll never change,
will you?
Would you want me to?
-Nope.
-Ha ha ha.
Hey, kiddo, look,
I know we were supposed...
to go to Baltimore today...
but you'll never believe
what came up.
It doesn't matter, Grandma.
oh, sure it does.
I know you wanted
to take me.
I--I really did.
Did I tell you that
my Cal Ripken card...
is my favorite one?
It is?
Yeah, and his signature
might've messed it up...
just like that Lamborghini girl
messed up Eric's arm.
The next time my convoy
swings by here...
you and I are gonna do
something really special.
I can't Wait.
Hi, Grandma, Cor.
Dad, I've been in my room...
For the last
twenty minutes, oK?
Alan, I would appreciate it...
if you kept your son
and his hormones...
inside the house...
at least until
my niece leaves.
Why, George,
what are you talking about?
Eric's been up
in his room for...
-Twenty...
-Minutes.
Excuse me.
I will not be jerked around.
oh, well, excuse me...
but as the matriarch
of this family...
not to mention
a card-carrying member...
of the Kiwanis Club,
I can personally vouch...
for the fact
that this fine young man...
has been up in his room
for the past twenty minutes.
And excuse me, Miss Kiwanis,
but how could you know that...
when I just saw you pull up
in your Winnebago...
and run over my mums
not forty seconds ago?
Who is this guy?
My teacher.
Does he give you
straight As?
-No.
-And why not?
Have you talked to the boy?
oK, teach,
you just better kiss...
The rest of those mums goodbye.
Wait.
Who is that woman?
My grandma.
Don't you just love her?
No, I don't.
Well, I do.
[Horn honks
"La Cucaracha"]
Cal Ripken Jr.,
rookie year.
I never thought I'd actually get
to hold one of these things.
My grandma picked it up at
the swap meet for seven bucks.
Seven bucks in dog years.
This baby's worth 1 50, easy.
-lt is?
-Yeah.
Boy, your grandma
must really love you.
Yeah.
or else she shot a man in Reno
just to watch him die.
You're kidding...right?
I'm not sureമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ