"And it was always said
of Scrooge...
"that he knew how
to keep Christmas well...
"if any man alive
possessed the knowledge.
"May that be truly said of us,
and all of us.
"And so as Tiny Tim observed...
"God bLess us. every one. "
And so ends Dickens' masterpiece
"A Christmas Carol."
Wait a minute.
Where's the Grinch?
Yeah. Isn't the Grinch
supposed to show up now...
and, like, take everything?
How come it's called
"A Christmas Carol" anyway?
Yeah. There was nobody
in this story named Carol.
Miss Lawrence, would you please
trade places with Mr. Matthews?
All right.
I am a hyperactive,
underachieving, 1 1-year-old boy.
I meant physically.
oh, well, that takes
less of a psychic toll.
Why do I have to move?
We were just giving
our view of the book.
Yeah. I mean,
you say literary masterpiece...
-we say...Anh!
-Anh!
Mr. Matthews, I'm less
interested in your review...
than I am that
you understand the material.
What, in your opinion,
was Mr. Dickens...
trying to express
in his Christmas story?
That if
you're a real butthead...
then neat ghosts
will take you to cool places.
Anh!
Fish and sticks.
Two things nature
never would've put together.
What'd you get?
Peanut butter and jelly.
Two things
nature couldn't keep apart.
Since when did
your mom pack you lunch?
I thought you liked fish sticks.
I do, but I think it's cruel...
how the little fish scream
when they rip their sticks off.
May I sit down?
BOTH: No.
Well, since you're ambivalent.
Ah, Christmas.
Season of togetherness.
Season of brotherhood.
Season of wool.
Nine out of ten
Christmas gifts--wool.
It doesn't matter if it's shaped
like socks or a sweater...
it's wool and it's itchy.
The gift isn't as important
as the thought behind it.
What's the thought behind wool?
This kid doesn't scratch enough?
I agree with Stuart.
oh, no. It's a nerd swarm.
Minkus,
shut off your geek magnet.
I just think
we often lose sight...
of the true meaning of Christmas
in the frenzy of commercialism.
What are you talking about?
How do We knowWhat to ask for
if We don't have commercials?
Christmas is the celebration
of the winter solstice...
an ancient tribal ritual
whose origins are lost in time.
Yeah, we were just talking
about that in the bathroom.
Listen, Topanga,
I think I can hear them...
calling you back
into your own dimension.
oh, yeah. They're saying...
"Topanga,
get your aura back here."
"And bring Minkus."
BOTH: Ha!
oK. Christmas tree update.
I think I got my real leather
NBA regulation basketball.
Cool. Major gift.
So major a gift...
I've been saving up
to buy my gift a gift.
What do you get the basketball
who has everything?
A $5.00 top of the line
imitation nylon net.
You have five bucks?
I've been saving up for a month.
Let's go buy it after school.
No. Then I tip off my parents
that I know what I'm getting.
You are a yuletide master.
Christmas is very delicate.
You screw up--wool.
So, what's the update
at your house?
Me? Hey, Bob Stubcheck's
Sports World...
has to send over a truck with
all the stuff my dad got me.
He got me, like, everything.
That's great.
Yeah. My dad totally
came through this year.
Speaking of gifts, you haven't
yet chipped in your $5.00...
for the class present
to Mr. Feeny.
-Tomorrow.
-You said that yesterday.
Come on, Shawn...
don't think of it
as $5.00 for Feeny's present.
Think of it as five bucks
to make Minkus go away.
Look, Minkus, I just spent
my last money on lunch, oK?
I'll give it to you tomorrow.
What? His mother
charged him a packing fee?
[Sighs]
Hi.
Hey! Did you have fun
at the mall?
I don't think I'd call it fun.
Well, hi, pumpkin.
I bet you had fun.
Did you get your picture
taken with Santa Claus?
Aaah!
I tried to tell you.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know that...
meant "Don't mention Santa."
What happened?
Well, Morgan was waiting
in line to sit on Santa's lap...
and she was kind of nervous,
and there was this elf...
who looked like a hitman,
only meaner.
What? Did Santa scare her?
No, no. He was
just this nice old man...
with a jolly red face.
You know, looking back,
his face really was too red.
I mean I just thought
he was overheated.
Velvet is a fabric
that doesn't breathe.
Amy, what happened?
Well, oK, so Morgan climbs up
on Santa's lap...
and he asks her
what she wants...
and she says
a Suzie Homemaker oven...
and then he grabbed his chest,
yelled "Rudolph," and fell over.
Are we talking eight reindeer
pulling a pine box?
No, no.
I think he's all right.
I mean, the hitman elf
gave him CPR...
while Mrs. Claus called
the paramedics.
Alan, it isn't funny!
Morgan thinks
she killed Santa Claus.
Well, did you tell her
that he's oK?
of course I did.
I said he was just resting...
and he'd be fine.
Maybe you can take her
to visit him in the hospital.
I really don't think
it'll help her to see...
Santa Claus with
a tube stuck up his nose.
Hey. What's with the weasel?
She locked herself
in the bathroom...
and she's singing...
&  On the first day
of Christmas &
&  I murdered Santa CLaus &
I'll go check on her. ohh!
Hi, Cory.
Hello, son, apple of my eye.
Dad, there's no reaching him
when he's taking inventory.
Yes! A new arrival!
It's Wool.
You know, Cor,
when I was a kid...
Christmas was about
appreciating your gifts...
because they were given
with love.
Love, right. Glad that's over.
oK. Three new boxes
and only one sounds itchy.
I'm going to go tell Shawn.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
Where are you going?
To call Shawn.
I don't think it'd be
such a good idea...
to exaggerate about the gifts
you're getting.
-I have to just to keep up.
-What do you mean?
I mean, Bob Stubcheck's
Sports World has been moved.
It's new location?
Under Shawn's tree.
I think Shawn may have been
exaggerating a little bit.
Dad, it's Christmas.
You're supposed to exaggerate.
I'm gonna tell him I got five
new presents under the tree.
You know, I don't think...
Shawn's gonna be having much of
a Christmas this year.
Why not?
[Sighs]
Shawn's dad got laid off.
Shawn's dad lost his job?
Yeah. I guess he was just
too embarrassed to tell you.
But I'm his best friend.
So that's why
his mom's packing his lunch.
Shawn's not getting anything
for Christmas...
just like Tiny Tim
in that story about Carol.
I don't think
it's quite that bad.
Dad, can I give him
one of the presents...
under the tree
so at least he has something?
That'd be really nice, Cor.
oK. How about one of Eric's?
MORGAN: &  We wish you
a merry Christmas &
&  We wish you
Morgan, if you come out...
I'll let you
play with my makeup.
&  And a happy new year &
Morgan, come out.
Santa's fine.
MORGAN: No. he's not.
Well, then how come
he just called me on the phone?
MORGAN: He did?
Yep.
MORGAN: What did he say?
He said,
"Ho ho h--ohh! ohh!"
Stop it.
What?
He said you've been
a very, very good girl...
and I should give you something
really special.
MORGAN: Like what?
Whatever you tell her,
she's gonna want it...
the second you open that door.
How about my new flannel shirt
that you like so much?
oK.
Ta-da!
What?
For you.
What is it?
open it. For you from me.
It's not going to blow up,
is it?
open it! open it!
Here. Let me open it.
A real leather NBA certified...
dribbles like a dream
basketball!
I'm giving it to you.
Don't you love me?
Why'd you give this to me?
Because it's Christmas.
So? We never give each other
stuff for Christmas.
Yeah, but this year's
kind of different.
Why?
Well...because.
Because why?
Because you're my best friend.
But I wasn't last year.
No, you were, it's just--
Cory, best friends
don't lie to each other.
oK. Look, Shawn, I gave you this
because I didn't think...
you'd be getting
that many gifts this year.
Hey, I told you.
I'm getting a ton of stuff.
I don't need a basketball.
My dad already got me two.
Look, Shawn, best friends
don't lie to each other.
What are you talking about?
I know about
your dad getting laid off.
-Says who?
-Says my dad.
oh, so what'd you do,
go tell everyone?
No. I didn't tell anyone.
Look, Shawn, I'm trying
to give you a nice gift...
so you don't have
a Tiny Tim Christmas...
and you're acting like
you're mad at me.
oh, so I'm supposed
to be all happy...
that you gave me
some bogus gift?
That's not a bogus gift.
That's a totally major gift.
It was my best gift...
and I was nice enough
to give it to you.
Yeah. Well, keep it.
I don't want your basketball.
Wouldn't you rather have
something for Christmas...
than nothing at all?
I'd rather have nothing
for Christmas...
than your lousy charity.
Hey, Shawn,
Christmas is about charity.
You should be thanking me!
Boy, where's
his Christmas spirit?
Where's his gratitude?
I can name one sixth grader...
who wasn't paying attention
to "A Christmas Carol."
I can name one, too,
Mr. Matthews.
-Yeah, Shawn.
-Cory.
Ha ha! No, I'm Cory.
You've been calling me
Mr. Matthews for so long...
you must've forgot.
Believe me,
I know who you are.
I also know that a true gift
is given with no expectation.
What's that mean?
It means you gave the gift
to get the thanks.
I gave the guy my official NBA
genuine leather basketball...
and he threw it back in my face.
What kind of friend is that?
You know what
I like most about Christmas?
I go away for a week?
Yeah, that's pretty special.
But it's the time of year
that you can think back...
and appreciate
the real gifts you received.
I don't get it.
Friendship, for example,
is a real gift.
And it's given
with no expectation...
and no gratitude is necessary.
Not between real friends.
You think about that.
[Sighs] We finally got Morgan
out of the bathroom.
-Great. How'd you do it?
-Psychology.
And bribery.
What happened to that mean elf?
oh, he went back
to the North Pole with Santa.
I think he Was mad at me.
No. He wasn't mad at you.
Then how come
he called me a demon child?
Well, he's gone now
and you don't ever...
have to worry about him
ever, ever again.
[Knock on door]
-I'll get it.
-Thank you.
Aaah!
-Mr. Matthews?
-Yeah?
I'm the elf.
No kidding.
I came to return
your wife's money.
She paid for a picture
with Santa.
She never got it.
Uh, excuse me.
You called my little girl
a demon child?
Hey, all I know
is one minute...
Santa's all jolly,
jingling his bells...
the next minute,
your kid sits on his lap...
ba-da-bing, ba-da-boom!
Heart attack.
Coincidence?
I don't think so.
ELF: Yeah? Merry stinking
Christmas to you. too. paL!
Shawn, it's tomorrow.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking
about the class present.
You still haven't paid
your $5.00.
Fine, I'll give it to you.
I just don't have it on me.
I'm going to buy
the present tonight...
so today is the last day
to give me the money.
I said I'll give it to you.
If you don't give me
$5.00 right now...
I'm not going to put your name
on the card...
and the entire sixth grade
of Jefferson Elementary...
is going to know
you're a deadbeat.
Fine, then I am. oK?
Minkus, leave him alone.
He doesn't have the money.
-He doesn't?
-No.
oh. That puts me in
an awkward position.
I can't put his name
on the card...
if he doesn't give me
the money.
Rules are rules.
I'm the class treasurer,
an elected official.
They could subpoena my diaries.
Um, look...
a couple weeks ago,
Shawn lent me five bucks...
and I never paid him back.
That's why
he doesn't have the money.
oh, so you're the deadbeat.
Yeah. But I've got it now,
so here it is.
Just make sure you put
Shawn's name on the card, oK?
Don't worry.
His name, however...
will have to be last since
he was the last one to pay.
Gee, Minkus, I wonder
whose name is first on the list?
Does it rhyme with stinkus?
I hope our reading
"A Christmas Carol"...
has interested all of you...
in reading other works
by Charles Dickens.
No, but I will watch
the David Copperfield special.
Mr. Minkus.
In my capacity
as class treasurer...
I Would like to present you...
with the sixth grade's
Christmas gift.
oh, my. Well...
ooh, it has the lovely heft
of a thick book.
You cunning bibliophile, you.
oh, my!
A dictionary.
How wonderful.
"To our admired
and respected teacher...
"from his dutiful
and attentive class."
I Wrote that.
I never would've guessed.
And all our names
are written below.
Yes. Minkus all the way
down to Hunter.
You all seem to be there.
Well, I am very touched.
This means a great deal to me.
So thank you very much.
[Bell rings]
Merry Christmas!
Have a wonderful vacation.
CoRY: Hurry!
Get out while you can! Hurry!
Don't forget to read
two books from the reading list.
Nobody heard that.
Hey, Minkus.
Thanks for putting my name
on the card.
Don't thank me.
Your deadbeat friend...
finally paid back
the money he owed you.
What?
It's oK. You don't have
to cover for him anymore.
He told me
how you lent him $5.00...
and he didn't give it back.
Cory told you that?
Yep, and he handed me
five bucks.
He gave you his $5.00?
I guess his conscience
finally got the better of him.
Hey, Minkus.
Merry Christmas.
Really?
Merry Christmas to you, too.
-Hey.
You know,
I was cleaning up my garage...
and I found something
you might like.
A net!
It belonged to my dad.
It's real old...
so it might not be
genuine imitation nylon.
Whoa, if it's that old,
it could be actual nylon!
It's yours.
Cool. Thanks.
Figure this way, you got the net
and I got the ball.
What ball?
You gave that to me.
I think I remember you throwing
this back in my face.
So every time you miss a pass,
we're not gonna be friends?
You want this ball...
you're gonna have to take it
from me, aren't you?
Nice try.
Think you can steal it from me?
Yeah.
Hey, I did it.
Nah. I let you have it.
It was charity.
It's Christmas.
[Playing "Hark!
The Herald Angels Sing"]
Not in the house.
You guys are playing
with that so much...
I'm afraid you're going
to wear a hole in it.
Who cares? It's his ball.
Close the door, please.
You guys ready for supper?
Shawn, I've got plenty.
If you want to stay,
I could call your mom.
Thanks, Mrs. Matthews,
but we're stringing up...
the lights tonight
and I want to be with my dad.
oK. Well, before you go,
I want you to take...
these Christmas cookies
to your mom.
I helped make them.
Yeah. Careful
when you bite into them.
one of Barbie's
little plastic shoes is missing.
Merry Christmas, you guys.
DAD: Merry Christmas. Shawn.
-Hoops here tomorrow?
-Do I have a choice?
You're the only guy
on the block with a net.
Shawn, you going to be oK?
Hey, when I got friends,
I can get through anything.
[Knock on door]
oh, wow,
somebody's at the back door.
Wow, I wonder who that could be
at the back door.
I have no clue.
-I forgot my line.
-Maybe Morgan...
oh, yeah! Maybe Morgan
should go get the back door.
[Pounding on door]
I'm not answering
any more doors.
Well, I think you're going
to want to answer this one.
It's Santa!
Look, everybody, he's alive!
MoM: Well, aren't you
going to let him in?
Hello, Morgan.
I am Santa.
And I've just returned
from the North Pole...
where I was just resting.
Santa, are you feeling better?
oh, yes, my dear.
As it turns out...
Mrs. Claus merely undercooked
my figgy pudding.
I'm going to get the camera.
Well, now, little Morgan...
tell Santa what you want
for Christmas.
Good grades
for your big brother.
Ho ho ho.
oK, everybody,
gather round for a picture.
Santa in the middle.
Mommy, why does
Santa look like Mr. Feeny?
&  JingLe beLLs. Batman smeLLs &
&  Robin Laid an egg &
&  BatmobiLe Lost its wheeL &
&  Commissioner
broke his Leg. oh &
Who taught you that?
-Cory.
-Well, he taught you wrong.
It goes like this.
&  JingLe beLLs. jingLe beLLs &
&  JingLe aLL the way &
&  Oh. what fun it is to ride &
&  In a one horse
open sLeigh. hey &
Boringമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ