[Ticking]
I'm Cory Matthews.
Today on "Eyewitness Cory"...
a probing expose of the plight
of the middle child.
Stay with us.
CORY:
So. Mr. and Mrs. Matthews...
where are we taking
youngest chiLd Morgan today?
Hey, Cor, we're going
to Stephanie's birthday party.
Doesn't your sister
look adorable?
Get a close-up of her new dress.
CORY: Excuse me. ma'am.
did you say new dress?
And is the baby of the famiLy
wearing a goLd neckLace?
My mommy gave it to me.
Lent it to you.
Party. neckLace. new dress--
aLL for your daughter.
yet just Last night...
your son was imprisoned
in his room...
forbidden to go to the movies
with his best friends.
our daughter didn't dial
random numbers...
in Saskatchewan just
to hear people talk Canadian.
Say good-bye to your poor,
exploited brother, sweetie.
Bye. Sorry everybody hates you.
FinaLLy.
the naked truth emerges.
Hey, Cor, do me a favor.
No phone calls,
no Home Shopping Network...
and be careful
with my video camera.
Have fun.
[Cory grunting]
There you have it.
All across America,
middle children suffering...
at the hands of suspicious,
mistrustful parents.
Aah! [Crash]
Next week... Grounded.
and how to cope with it.
[Music playing]
Taxation Without representation.
King George.
We provide the colonists...
with all their finished
manufactured goods.
We deserve remuneration.
General Washington.
Fine. Keep your goods.
Like we need
your stinking British goods.
We're American.
We're independent.
We'll get our goods from Japan.
[Laughing]
General, I'm dying for you
to elaborate.
What's the point, Mr. Feeny?
We all know
we kicked British butt.
Winners and losers aside,
General.
If we do not understand
history...
we are doomed to repeat
its mistakes.
oh, who cares about
George Washington?
Who cares about King George?
Was every boring guy in history
named George?
I meant, every dead boring guy.
Apparently, the past
holds no fascination for you.
No. It's happened. It's done.
-It's history.
-I'm saying.
Perhaps we should study
your history, Mr. Matthews.
I have no history, Mr. Feeny.
I'm eleven.
I'm more interested in
my future.
oh, well, then it might be
more interesting...
for us to look into
our futures...
to see if we can avoid
our mistakes...
before they happen.
I smell an assignment.
I swear,
I didn't see it coming.
The assignment for all of you...
is to create personal histories
for yourselves...
as if you were returning for
your 20th high school reunion.
More like a preunion.
Well said, Mr. Minkus.
You are the graduating class
of the year 2000.
What is your profession?
Do you have children?
Are those children tormenting
their sixth-grade teacher?
Mr. Feeny, would it be oK
if I brought my wife?
oh, come on, Minkus,
what's going to marry you?
Topanga.
CLASS: ooh!
Why, Stuart, I'm flattered
that you would consider me...
as a potential life mate,
but I'm not sure...
I even recognize
the institution of marriage.
Trust me, babe,
I've seen the future...
and it's me.
You're going to show up
as a tire salesman?
-That's what my dad does.
-So?
I knowWhat to Wear.
I know how
to use a pressure gauge.
I can spot a retread
from a mile away.
Shawn, you're so boring.
And lazy.
How about you, Larry?
-I got an angle.
-Let's hear it.
I'm going to be
a sixth-grade teacher.
Better yet,
I'm going to be Feeny.
Why?
Imitation is the sincerest form
of butt-kissing.
Wait a minute.
Weren't we supposed to be
what we wanted to be?
I mean, you're going to
grow up to be your dad...
and you're going to grow up
to be a Feeny clone.
Am I the only one left
here with some vision?
What are you going to go as?
Cory Matthews...
center fielder
for the Philadelphia Phillies.
BOTH: Ha ha ha!
What are you laughing at?
You had 31 errors
in Little League last season.
oK, so I didn't play
up to my enormous potential.
Come on, guys, let's be what
we really want to be.
Are we going to be men...
or are we going to be men
with boring jobs?
We're going to be men!
[Barking]
oK, here's a picture of you
I'm willing to part with...
for you to put on
your baseball card.
Boy, Feeny'll be blown away...
by this future
I'm putting together.
Let's see, when you have
your 20th high school reunion...
I'll be...44.
Mom, how can that be possible?
You're already--
It's possible.
It's not only possible...
it's the way it's going to be.
Look, Mommy.
That's very pretty, sweetheart.
Where did that come from?
I traded your necklace.
Morgan,
that was a gold necklace...
and this one is plastic.
Can't you see the difference?
Yes. This one is pretty.
Who did you
make this trade with?
Stephanie.
Honey, I'm going to have to call
Stephanie's mom...
and untrade this trade.
But we said,
"Black, black, no trades back."
Hello, Jane?
Hi, it's Amy Matthews.
Look, our daughters did a
silly little trade yesterday...
so I'm sure you'll understand...
I'll be needing
my necklace back.
What do you mean,
"Black, black, no trades back"?
MINKUS: Then after my Leveraged
buyout of Microsoft...
I Went public and became...
the largest software
manufacturer in the free world.
Mr. Minkus, taking over
a company is no simple task.
It requires proof of assets...
bank guarantees,
countless applications.
Mr. Feeny, who do you think
you're dealing with?
A list of my creditors,
my loan guarantees...
and my approval by
the Federal Trade Commission.
An "A", Mr. Minkus, for
a very well thought out future.
Thank you, Mr. Feeny,
and on the personal front...
my lovely wife Topanga and l
just celebrated the birth...
of our third child,
Rainbow Einstein Minkus.
A tire salesman.
I can't believe
you came as a tire salesman.
And muffler specialist.
What's with the big gut?
My dad's fat, my uncle's fat,
my grandpa's fat.
Let's face it, Cor,
I'm going to be fat.
President of the United States.
Very ambitious, Miss Lawrence.
Yes and no. Not many people
want the job anymore.
oh, why is that?
Well, now that
I've disbanded the military...
and eliminated
nuclear weapons...
the position
is not as seductive.
I see. That's rather
an unusual costume...
for a president, isn't it?
We all wear togas now.
It removes
the hostile competition...
that fashion often creates.
This world of yours
seems like...
quite a peaceful
and loving place.
Yes, especially since
we moved all men underground...
and use them just for breeding.
Well, a few moments ago,
Mr. Minkus mentioned...
that you were his lovely wife.
Stuart and I obviously
do not see...
eye-to-eye on our futures.
-We're married.
-You're breeding stock.
I'll take it.
Can I help you, Mr. Williams?
I've come back to the reunion
as a beloved teacher...
not unlike yourself, sir.
oh, how flattering.
You're following
in my footsteps...
and, look,
you've dressed just like me.
Come over here,
you little suck up.
Every year someone tries
to avoid the assignment...
with this transparent
little ruse.
I didn't mean to be ruse.
Can you tell me the meaning
of the word "tenure"?
I can look it up.
-Can you define curriculum?
-I can look it up.
Just as I thought.
You're no teacher.
You're nothing more
than a poseur.
Go look it up.
Ready for me?
Yes, I'm ready, Mr. Matthews.
All right.
Center fielder for the Phillies.
Most impressive.
Yeah, my fans seem to think so.
Then you're quite well-known?
Breakfast of me.
How's it feel to be
in the presence of a legend?
Well, legends
are not born overnight.
You must've been playing
for quite a while.
oh, ever since the 1 1th grade.
You didn't graduate high school?
High school's kind of a joke...
when you're pulling down
six mil a year.
Six million?
Hurts, doesn't it?
Well, adjusted for inflation...
that's a paltry sum
compared to even...
the average ballplayer's
salary today.
-But I've got investments.
-Such as?
You know, investments.
Buildings.
Buildings with floors
and people in them doing stuff.
I'm diversified.
And do you handle
these investments yourself?
No. My guys do that stuff.
oh, you've got guys?
Lots of guys.
They're in my buildings.
And what percentage
of your salary...
do they charge
for their services?
Mr. Feeny,
you're dragging me down.
Can't we discuss, like,
my batting average?
You're floundering,
Mr. Matthews.
No. I thought this through.
Look, I even made up
my own baseball card.
Yet you have no clue...
as to how your affairs
will be managed...
no education
to help you get a clue...
and no marketable skills...
after your ball-playing
days are over.
But I've got guys.
Well, Mr. Matthews...
you've made an attempt
at this assignment.
You just didn't think it
all the way through.
And until you do, I'm going
to give you an incomplete.
-An incomplete?
-Mm-hmm.
That's an "l".
That's lower than an "F".
That's down there by "M".
You can't do this.
Why not?
'Cause it's not like
you're giving me...
an incomplete
on some dinky quiz.
You threw me out
before I even got to first base.
You took away my future.
[Sighs]
[Music playing]
I'll miss you, Jim,
but you should be...
on the wall
of a kid with a future.
What are you doing?
There's nothing
out there for me, Eric.
That's great, Cor,
but I'm trying to read here, oK?
What's the point?
This is the point.
In three years,
I could save up enough...
to get one of
these vintage Mustangs...
and fill it
with cheerleaders. Ha ha!
Yeah? How're you gonna pay
for the insurance?
What? I don't know.
Maybe Dad'll help me.
What if Dad can't afford
to help you, Eric?
I don't know. Maybe
I'll get another part-time job.
Work two jobs and go to school.
oh, Eric, Eric, Eric.
You're nothing but a poseur.
Poseur, huh? Really?
What do you think of this pose?
Hey, guys,
you ready for dinner?
No, but I'll do anything
to get away from Captain Bummer.
Your mom told me about
the assignment.
It wasn't
just an assignment, Dad.
It was my future.
I got an incomplete.
I have an incomplete future.
of course you have
an incomplete future.
The future's always incomplete.
When it's complete,
people tend to call it the past.
Mine was supposed to be
all planned out.
I thought you wanted to be
a baseball player?
I do, but that's not enough
for Feeny the Dream Crusher.
I don't care
what George Feeny says.
You can do anything you put
your mind to, Cory, anything.
Maybe I'll give these to Morgan.
She can color in
Jim Abbott's uniform.
Dad, when you were a kid...
did someone tell you
that you'd never make it...
to being the manager
of a supermarket?
Well, that wasn't exactly
what I dreamed of being.
It's not?
But it's such a cool job.
I wanted to build bridges...
big ones,
like the Ben Franklin.
Then how come you gave that up?
I don't know.
Sometimes, as you get older,
your dreams change.
After a while, I dreamed of
having a wife and a family...
and that came true.
You know what
I dream of being now?
What?
I dream of being the father
of a Phillies center fielder.
Dad, there's another dream
you can kiss good-bye.
Hey, not so fast.
I don't give up that easy.
I still think my kid's going
to play in the majors.
I used to dream
like that, Dad...
but now I know
that sooner or later...
every dream comes to an end
and you got to wake up.
Hello, Jane.
Hi, Stephanie,
it's nice to see you again.
Where's Morgan?
-ln the kitchen.
-Go ahead, sweetheart.
I'm glad
our little disagreement...
didn't prevent the kids
from playing together.
Well, that would be selfish.
Would you like some coffee?
You are not getting
the necklace back.
Now, don't misunderstand.
It's not the value of it...
it's Stephanie's
attachment to it.
oh, I'm sure I do understand...
and I had no intention
of asking for it.
In that case,
I'll have some coffee.
-Ha ha ha!
-oK.
Wow, you have neat stuff.
Yes. Here we have my mommy's
double chocolate brownies.
ooh, brownies!
Not so fast.
And here
we have a diamond crown.
ooh, diamonds.
Hold your horses.
And speaking of horses...
My Little Pony.
So, do you work?
oh, no, I don't have to.
My husband's
a very successful attorney.
Ahh. So that's
where little Stephanie...
gets her flair for negotiations.
Mommy, look, diamonds!
Stephanie,
where's your dress...
and your hat and your necklace?
I traded them.
My dress, my hat, my necklace.
You traded them
for a plastic tiara?
And a brownie.
And a little pink pony.
No. I had to give her
something else for the pony.
What?
I'll be needing
the keys to your car.
Don't misunderstand.
It's not the value of the car...
it's Morgan's attachment to it.
Look, I'm telling you,
she was doing the kissing.
I--I was like
an innocent bystander.
Yes, I could've walked away...
but she had me pinned up
against the lockers. I mean--
-But--
-Call her back later.
Are you crazy?
I didn't even know who that was.
Shawn, call everyone
and get over to my house now.
Jim Abbott's in my kitchen.
Ha ha ha! Jim Abbott?
Are you out of your mind?
No, I'm totally in my mind.
Yeah, one of the best pitchers
in Major League Baseball...
is in our house. Ha ha ha!
Guys, somebody here
I'd like you to meet.
Cory, Eric.
Wouldn't you like
to meet Jim Abbott?
I guess not.
BOTH: Aah!
-Hi, guys.
-Hi.
How are you doing?
You must be Cory.
I'm whoever you want me to be.
Your dad's told me
a lot about you.
He has? But how did he...
How did Dad...
Why are you in my house?
Cory, don't bug the man with
a lot of little-boy questions.
So, Jim,
why are you in our house?
Well, I heard that Cory here...
wants to be in
the big leagues someday.
Who, me? Nah, stupid idea.
I gave up on that.
Guys like me
don't make it to the majors.
Well, there's a guy
I know who has a son...
who always dreamed of playing
in the major leagues...
until a certain teacher
told him...
that maybe
it wasn't such a good idea.
This sounds familiar to me.
Well, it sounded
familiar to me, too.
-lt did?
-Sure.
one time
I had a high school coach...
who said I should never play
in the major leagues...
and that only made me
work 50 times harder.
Really? You ever go back
to that coach...
and rub it in his face?
Nah, Jim's too cool to do that,
aren't you, Jim?
No, actually, I sent him
a videotape of my no-hitter.
Cool. I guess you showed him.
Well, actually, he showed me.
He showed me
an application to a place...
called
the University of Michigan.
Why'd he do that?
Well, he was smart enough
to know...
that if I didn't make it
to the major leagues someday...
at least I'd have
a major league education.
So you think I can get into
the University of Michigan?
I mean, now that I got
connections and everything?
I think
you'll be all right, Cory.
You got one big thing
going for you.
oh? You heard
about how well I bunt?
Well, that and the fact
that you've got a great dad...
who lets his kids
have big dreams...
and he's also
just crazy enough...
to send a total stranger
63 telegrams.
Gee, you only got 63 of them?
You did that for me, Dad?
But how'd you know he'd show up?
I didn't know.
But a guy can dream, can't he?
Hey, Jim, you mind
signing these for these guys?
Sure.
-Me, too!
-I want one, too!
Apparently,
I've brought the wrong ball.
Matthews goes back deep.
He's on his horse!
He's at the Wall!
That ball is...
Gone.
Come on, Mr. Feeny, please.
You know the rules.
You start respecting
my property line...
and I'll start respecting
your property.
Yes, sir. Mr. Feeny,
I just want you to know...
I made up my mind...
and I'm going to be
a baseball player.
Is that so?
Yeah. Because a friend
of my dad's--
I don't want
to drop any names--
so let's just call him
Jim Abbott--
well, Jim and I and my dad
had a little talk...
and we straightened out
my whole future.
You did?
Yep, I'm going to be
in the major leagues...
Mr. Feeny,
no matter what you say.
But Jim and my dad--
and when I say Jim--
-You mean Jim Abbott.
-I'm saying!
Well, they say that maybe
I shouldn't turn pro...
until after college.
So you've changed your plans
and intend to graduate?
Yeah. 'cause I'm going to make
a name for myself...
playing college ball
before I turn pro.
Just like Jim did.
Seems like
this Abbott fellow...
had his future
very well-planned...
and worked hard
to get where he is.
You have no idea how hard,
Mr. Feeny.
Well, you did better
than I expected...
and I guess you
deserve something.
Is this your little way
of telling me...
you're changing
my incomplete to an "A"?
No. This is
my little way of saying...
Play ball!
[Television playing]
Why do women go on these shows?
You see the guy with the ripped
jeans and the tight butt?
-Yeah.
-That's why.
Does it ever bother you
that I never built bridges?
What?
I never became an engineer.
Does it bother you?
once in a while.
You think
you married a failure?
You've got a really good job
where people respect you.
You have
three beautiful children...
who are fast asleep
in their little beds...
and you have a wife...
who has absolutely
nothing to do...
for the next half hour.
So what are you saying, hmm?
Mom, Dad.
CouLd you do
something interesting?
This kissing stuff...
is not going to hoLd
my audience's attention.
It was holding my attention
until the news crew showed up.
Come on. guys.
This is teLevision.
How about a LittLe action?
oh, oK. You want action?
How about a chase scene?
-Give me that camera!
-Cut!
-Give me the camera!
-Cut, cut!
-Give me the camera.
-Cut! Cut!
Give me the cameraഡഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ