You got your milk.
You got your peanut butter.
How about a banana?
What about a raw egg?
Eww. Why's it have to be raw?
Why can't we scramble it
and put it in?
Stallone drinks raw eggs.
Stallone is like 5'2"!
And you're like 2'5"!
Go with the egg, baby.
Hey!
We're not going to make a mess.
Just because
we're kids with a blender...
doesn't mean
we have to make a mess.
Boy, are you Mommy whipped.
Aah!
Now, that I could never do
at my house.
oh, my mom!
Shawn, back me up.
I wanted to use the lid.
I was Lid Boy!
oK, fine. I'll clean it up.
You don't have to scream.
Hey, watch it.
You're getting it
all over my geography book.
oh, like you're ever going
to open it up.
Feeny's test tomorrow
is going to be such a killer.
Yeah, I don't understand
why we have to learn...
anything about geography.
Why do we have to
learn where everything is?
I'll just be like my dad
and drive around till I find it.
Look at Feeny.
He's out there hanging up
some geeky duck.
Not a care in the World...
while we're stuck in here
studying for his lame test.
Yeah. Life's fair.
Well, we haven't actually done
any studying yet.
Maybe we should get started.
oK. Ahem.
What is
the capital of North Dakota?
Banff.
We're toast.
Let's just say we're sick
and stay home tomorrow.
I can't, Cor.
I've already used
all my bogus medical excuses.
Feeny says if my grandma dies
one more time...
he wants to see the body.
How come it has to be us?
Why should
we always be the ones...
faking a disease
to get out of school?
How come Feeny can't shoulder
a little more responsibility?
Ah, dream on.
I hear he hasn't missed...
a day of school
since World War l.
That's just stupid
on his part...
because teachers still get paid
when they're sick.
You lie.
I swear!
Minkus said the school board...
pays them to be sick
for a whole week every year.
Well, maybe
Feeny doesn't know that.
Maybe we should leave him
a unanimous note on his desk.
Won't help us dodge
that geography bullet tomorrow.
Come on...cough!
[lnhales]
[Exhales]
There's a look.
Don't tell me.
You've died and come back
as a bat with a perm.
This Hindu yoga position...
increases
blood flow to the brain...
thus maximizing concentration
and cognitive performance.
It's also quite a rush.
I am so nervous.
You? My palms
are sweating so much...
I can't read the answers
I Wrote on them.
I'm sensing an acute case
of performance anxiety...
no doubt brought on by
a complete lack of preparation.
Minkus, you can get
all the As you want.
It still not
gonna make you popular.
That's right.
I can just hear you
10 years from now.
"People, people, how many times
do I have to tell you?
"lf you save your receipts...
"you won't have to worry
about an audit."
And I can hear you
ten years from now.
"Your Honor, dude...
"I'd like to plea bargain."
-Geek master.
-Recidivist.
Good morning, class.
I'm Miss Chase,
your substitute teacher.
Mr. Feeny will not be in today.
He has taken ill.
Taken ill or fakin' ill?
I mean,
the guy's never missed a day.
Maybe he heard about
the school board's...
great deal on sick leave.
I'm afraid I don't have access
to Mr. Feeny's lesson plan.
Can somebody
please fill me in...
on what you were going
to do today?
Miss Chase, today
we're supposed to take a geo--
Break.
A break from geography.
And do nothing
but think about our lives...
and write a poem about it.
A short poem.
CORY:
Two. maybe three Lines. tops.
And it doesn't
even have to rhyme.
Is this true?
Yep.
MlSS CHASE: Great.
My major at the University
of Pennsylvania...
was poetry...epic poetry.
In fact, my dissertation
was on "Beowulf"...
an 8th Century poem...
written in 3,200 lines
of old English.
Let's see
if We can knock out...
the first 1,600 lines
before lunch, shall we?
BOTH: Aah!
[Music playing]
I can't believe Mr. Feeny
actually missed a day of school.
Well, you know who you can
thank for that, don't you?
Zeus?
Me! I wished for him
to get sick, and he did.
You didn't wish for him
to get sick.
Sure, I did, yesterday,
when we weren't studying.
Even if you did,
you can't make...
something happen
just because you say it.
The power of the mind...
is not to be
taken lightly, Shawn.
Force of will is the most
powerful weapon on earth.
No. No, it's not.
Maybe I do have
some kind of strange power...
Iike the X-Men...
only I have the power
to make people sick.
Yeah.
It's working on me right now.
Maybe I'll call myself Sick Boy!
Sick Boy, possessor of
a strange mutant power...
can, with a glance
of his sickening eye...
make otherwise healthy men
bend over the toilet...
and go, "Huahh!"
All right, Sick Boy.
If you can do it, do it to him.
Piece of cake.
Hey, Minkus.
Minkus, come here.
When your mother
cuts your hair...
tell her to take the oatmeal
out of the bowl.
Sorry, Shawn,
but I don't have the energy...
to trade insults today.
I'm not feeling very well.
-Whoa.
-Chills.
What can I say? It's a gift.
Minkus, you were all right
in class this morning.
When, exactly,
did you start feeling terrible?
When I heard
Mr. Feeny's in the hospital.
The hospital? Sounds serious.
For Mr. Feeny and for you.
Why me?
Why's it serious for me?
Karma--
what goes around comes around.
The hospital?
Whoa, you are good.
Me? I didn't do this.
You wished he would get sick.
I didn't wish for him
to get sick.
Sure, you did, yesterday,
when we weren't studying.
Shawn, you said it yourself.
Just because you want
something to happen...
doesn't mean
it's going to happen.
You're scary, Cor.
I wish you wouldn't
say things like that.
Just don't look at me, oK?
Don't look at me!
"Free Bubba, Love, Arnie"?
"Feel better, Love, Amy."
oh, that's
what you think you wrote.
Cory, read this.
"Fried baloney, Love, Alvin."
-Just sign it!
-What is it?
It's a get well card
for Mr. Feeny.
Here, you sign it, too.
-I don't think so, Mom.
-Suit yourself.
I just wanted to get him
out of the hospital faster.
How's a card going to do that?
It cheers him up.
Power of positive thinking.
Wait a minute.
Mom, Mom, Mom.
You're saying
someone can get better...
just 'cause
someone wishes they will?
Yeah.
Does the opposite
of that work, too?
Can someone get sick...
just 'cause
someone says they will?
Well, that is the principle
behind voodoo curses.
But you'd have to go to,
like, a voodoo academy...
to pull off something like that,
wouldn't you?
I mean, your average
12-year-old on the street...
couldn't go around making people
drop like flies, could he?
No reason. No interest.
My lips are just moving.
Words are coming out.
CORY: Eric. we've got to taLk.
All right, I wished real hard
for Feeny to get sick...
so I wouldn't have to take
this geography test...
and he got sick.
-So?
-So, I did this to him.
I have the gift.
What gift?
I can make people sick.
Now, see,
I've always known that, Cor.
Why do you think
I sleep with a barf bag?
Eric, I'm serious.
Yeah, like you're the one
who made Feeny's appendix blow.
He has appendicitis?
Yeah, he's getting
operated on right now.
An operation. That's bad.
Remember Fluffy, our cat?
He died during an operation.
Cory, Fluffy fell out of a tree.
They were trying
to sew his head back on.
It was big odds going in.
Look, I know I did not cause
Mr. Feeny to get sick...
but it would make me
feel a heck of a lot better...
if you would just give me...
some sort of sign
that he's gonna be all right.
MISS CHASE: Yesterday we were
absoLuteLy enthraLLed...
by the first 1.600
exciting Lines of "Beowulf."
[Snoring]
Can anyone recap for us?
Hrothgar, king of the Danes,
on the island of Zealand...
has built the mead hall Heorot
for feasting his warriors...
but they abandon it
because of...
the murderous ravages
of the monster Grendel.
Is it just me,
or does anyone else...
want to absolutely hurl
from boredom?
Do you have
a problem with "Beowulf"?
Yeah.
My problem is nobody cares.
I don't need this.
When am I going to need this?
No one has ever needed this.
And let me make myself
even clearer.
"Beowulf" needed? No!
And on
a completely side issue...
who names their baby Hrothgar?
Are you through?
No. As a matter of fact,
I'm not.
I don't think
we need geography, either.
This is a school.
What we should do here?
I think we should sit around,
talk about whatever we want...
and you should make us cupcakes.
Cory Matthews,
you are so...right.
Shawn, Shawn, wake up!
I fixed everything.
Thank you for stopping me
from wasting my entire life.
I mean, I would have ended up
just like Mr. Feeny...
who believes in
geography and mathematics...
and that other garbage
you'll never need.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is a teacher!
Here. Why don't you pass
these out to everybody?
When did you bake these?
Just this second.
I most heartily object...
to this flagrant desecration
of the temple of knowledge.
Stuff it, nerd boy.
Mr. Matthews,
who's the new teacher?
Karen.
Karen?
Yeah.
We're on a first name basis.
Cozy.
And we're not taking
that geography test, either.
In fact, we've done away
with geography.
No one needs it.
You must think
you've died and gone to heaven.
Yep. No offense,
but you could learn...
a lot about teaching
from Karen.
Well, I guess I've been an ogre
all these years, hmm?
What was I thinking?
Nobody knows.
But all that stress
you put on us...
probably just bounced back
and made you sick.
Karma--what goes around
goes around and around.
You need to lighten up.
Well, thank you for the advice,
Mr. Matthews.
Uh...Iike this?
Cut it out, Cory.
That wasn't me.
That was Mr. Feeny.
Mr. Feeny?
Talk about a sick joke.
What do you mean?
He's standing right here.
oh, nurse!
He can't see me, Mr. Matthews.
Why not?
Because he's not the one
responsible.
Responsible for What?
For killing me.
I died in the hospital.
What?
I'm dead, Mr. Matthews...
thanks to you.
Don't die, Mr. Feeny!
I didn't mean to kill you!
oh, man.
Eric, I just dreamed
I killed Mr. Feeny...
and he came back to haunt me.
It Was terrible. Eric?
Aah!
What are you doing here?
I'm memorizing the dictionary,
Mr. Matthews.
Mr. Feeny, I just woke up.
You can't be here anymore.
I can be anywhere I want.
I'm dead.
You're not dead.
You can't be dead.
I only wanted you
to have the sniffles.
It started With the sniffles.
[Sniffs]
Cor, you look terrible.
Coffee?
What are you doing with coffee?
I always drink coffee
after I kill a man.
Mr. Feeny's in the hospital
because of a bad appendix.
No matter what you wished,
you had nothing to do with it.
But how come I can't get him
out of my mind?
Why am I seeing him everywhere?
Because you feel guilty.
Because I wished he'd get sick.
Yeah, why'd you do that?
So I wouldn't have to take
his stupid geography test...
about stuff I'd never need.
Yeah, I know how you feel.
I had a teacher
in fourth grade--Miss Perch.
Now, the name Perch implies
that she was...
a lot better-looking
than she actually was.
And this relates to me how?
You know why I'm the manager
down at the supermarket?
Because when I started out
as a box boy...
I could add long columns
of numbers in my head...
faster than the cashiers
could at the machines.
I always told everyone
it was a natural gift...
but the fact is, I knew
it was a gift from Miss Perch.
So, why did you feel guilty?
Well, when she was trying
to teach me math...
I Was the kid
in the back of the room...
always going,
"I'm never gonna need this."
By the time I figured out
why I needed it...
it was too late to say
thank you.
So you're saying
Feeny's teaching us stuff now...
that we're gonna need
when we're older.
And instead of saying thank you,
I wished for him to get sick.
Is that why
I'm having nightmares?
Your nightmares are just
a manifestation of your guilt.
You created them.
You can control them.
MR. FEENY: What's for
breakfast. Mr. Matthews?
Down here.
How you doing?
You don't scare me anymore,
Mr. Feeny.
You're not real.
You're just
a manifestation of my guilt.
ooh. "Manifestation."
Big word for someone
who can barely spell "cat."
I created him.
I can make him go away.
Whew.
[Laughing]
[Knock knock]
Knock knock.
Mr. Matthews.
What a surprise.
Where are your parents?
They didn't bring me.
I took the bus.
Actually,
they don't even know I'm here.
I brought you a germanium.
Geranium.
Didn't I say germanium?
Yes, you did.
In fact, germanium
is a chemical element.
Atomic weight--72.59.
It's used as a semiconductor.
Your brain must weigh so much.
A geranium is a lovely plant.
In California, they can grow
to the size of a bush.
So...this is a hospital, huh?
oh. Is this your grandson?
-No.
-No way.
-Not at all.
-What he said.
This is one of my students
Cory Matthews.
Cory, this is Nurse Jill.
Well, it's nice to see
one of your students...
came to visit you, George.
She calls you
by your first name?
Don't blow it for me,
you little weasel.
[Laughs]
I stashed two bottles of
that pineapple juice you like...
in case you and your nongrandson
want to have one.
I am eternally grateful.
Cory, you stay
as long as you like.
And if a big dragon in a hat
that says "Head Nurse"...
tries to kick you out...
you tell her
you're a friend of Jill's, oK?
oK.
See you later, George.
She seems nice.
Yes, indeed. Very nice.
Did we just have,
like, a guy moment?
Yes, I suppose we did.
Why are you here, Mr. Matthews?
I mean, a hospital
is a very scary place.
I guess I wanted to see
with my own eyes that you're oK.
Thank you
for your good thoughts.
And that you're not dead.
oh, I can't die, Mr. Matthews.
I have too much Work
left undone...
too many students left untaught.
-Like me?
-Especially you.
In a strange way,
you've kept me alive.
I'm glad.
Because there
still might be some stuff...
you're going to teach me
that I'm gonna need someday.
Like What?
Like, say
I'm walking down the street...
and some guy
comes up to me and says...
"What's the atomic weight
of geranium?"
Thanks to you,
I'll be able to say...
"That's a plant, you idiot."
[Laughs]
Dragon alert. Lay low.
Maybe I'd better go so I don't
get Nurse Jill in trouble.
Thank you very much for coming,
Mr. Matthews.
You've made me feel much better.
I feel better, too.
Mr. Feeny...
Thank you.
For What?
I don't know yet.
Hey, Cor, what are you doing?
I'm trying to fix
Mr. Feeny's dumb duck.
He's coming home tomorrow.
That's nice. Looks like
it could use some bracing.
Bracing, right.
Can I borrow your tools?
Sure.
Good morning, Mr. Matthews.
Mr. Feeny, you're home early.
Well, I got most
of my strength back.
Besides, they replaced
Nurse Jill with Nurse Larry.
I figured it was time to leave.
I'm trying to fix your duck.
Yes, so I see. Thank you.
Why don't you take a break
and help me plant this?
You're putting my puny plant
in the ground?
Your plant, though immature
and undeveloped...
has within it the potential
to grow and flower...
with the help
of a proper gardener.
You think so?
oh, yes, as long as no one
wishes it ill.
IfWe think it can happen,
it Will happen.
You're saying we can light
that light bulb...
without any electricity?
The greatest power company
of all is the human mind.
Apparently
Shawn didn't pay his bill.
Those are cute last Words.
Shh.
Let's focus our psychic energies
on lighting the bulb.
There's no place like home.
Quiet.
None of the electricity
made it to the bulb, Topanga.
It all got stuck in your hair.
There's your problem.
No one here
is taking this seriously.
They don't care about
your experiment, Topanga.
The only way to demonstrate...
the power of
their selfish minds...
is to have them
concentrate on something...
they really want to see happen.
BOTH: Cool!
What?
The bulb didn't lightമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ