Hormones--the teLegraph system
of the body.
[T elegraph key]
Sometime between
the ages of nine and sixteen...
they wiLL start to teLL
your body to change--very fast.
[Faster telegraph key]
This movie's rated "H" for hurl.
Mr. Matthews,
calm down and watch the film.
The changes
won't aLL be physicaL.
Sometimes you'LL feeL
Like you're on...
an emotionaL roLLer coaster.
[Roller coaster]
For instance...
you may occasionaLLy
feeL aggressive or weepy.
Shawn,
I'm feeling so vulnerable.
Do you have a tissue?
Shh!
And remember. girLs. you'LL
get your hormonaL teLegram...
weLL ahead
of your boy cLassmates.
MAN:
TeLegram for Miss Teenager.
NARRA TOR: GirLs. be patient
whiLe they catch up to you.
EventuaLLy. everyone hears
the Morse code of puberty.
I got your Morse code
right here.
[Pbfft]
This film is meant to help you
understand...
the metamorphosis your bodies
will soon be going through.
How? That movie's
a hundred years old.
The telegram boy
was played by George Burns.
I welcome the changes
that will transform me...
from a caterpillar
into a butterfly.
You say a butterfly.
I say a hairball with wings.
-Hah!
That's a beautiful outlook,
Miss Lawrence.
Beautiful? I've seen hormones...
turn a normal guy's face
into craters 'r' us.
Yes, there will be side effects,
but those, thank goodness...
will be the province
of your seventh-grade teacher.
-lf it happens.
-oh, it will happen.
Maybe, maybe not.
I mean, I'm young, and I'm fast.
I can dodge hormones for days--
years if I have to.
I'm going to stay tweLve
tiLL I'm forty-two.
And Shawn's in with me on this
the whoLe way.
Right. Shawn?
Shawn?
[Snapping]
[Theme music playing]
Tell me something.
How do you ask a girl out?
Simple. You open the door...
and say,
"Get out. You're bothering me."
No, I mean, like, on a date.
Well, Eric uses
the shotgun approach.
He just keeps dialing
random numbers...
till he hears the word "yes."
Sounds like a lot of work.
Yeah, and after all that,
what do you got?
A girl. What's the point?
Excuse me.
I couldn't help overhearing
your pathetic conversation.
Perhaps you two neophytes
would like some coaching...
from a seasoned veteran.
oK, Minkus, let's pretend
for just a minute...
that I'm actually interested
in what you've got to say.
Well, girls are soft, caring,
gentle creatures of nature...
yet so complex and mysterious.
Minkus, get a cat.
Here. My research material.
-Perky magazine?
-Perky tells girls...
everything they want to know
about themselves.
Therefore, if we read it...
we'll know
everything about them, too.
It's the road map
to their very souls.
"Shaving your legs--
how high is high enough?"
Your little friend there
hasn't gotten his telegram yet.
"Mascara--
use it, don't abuse it."
Well, um, as long as
I don't actually have to go...
to the newsstand and buy it...
I might as well borrow it
for a couple days.
"Guys with one eyebrow--
what's their problem?"
You know,
this is the encyclopedia...
to everything
you don't want to know.
Yeah. Can you imagine
reading this kind of garbage?
I know. Every morning
when I look for a magazine...
to hide in my math book,
I think...
Sports lllustrated?
Road and Track?
or, wait, how about
the lip gloss issue of Perky?
Hi, Shawn.
Huh-huh-huh-huh.
Would you like to go
to the movies with me?
Huh-huh-huh-huh.
Great. We can meet at my locker
after school...
and my mom
will drop us off at the mall.
See ya later, terminator.
Hee hee hee hee hee.
Hee hee hee.
Did she just tell a joke
I didn't get?
Hee hee hee hee hee.
-Shawn, stop laughing.
-I can't.
Whoa. I don't even know
what just happened.
I'm feeling really weird, Cory.
Heh heh heh heh heh.
You look really weird.
Shawn, what's happening?
I don't know. Ha ha ha.
You're scaring me.
Shawn, talk to me.
I can't talk about it.
I can laugh about it,
but I cannot talk about it.
oK, so we're in front
of the movie theater.
First hurdle--
did she pay, or did you pay?
Eric, we snuck in.
She agreed to a criminal act.
I like this girl.
Then I go to get the popcorn,
right?
All right. Very important--
did she offer to pay?
We split it
right down the middle.
She's a keeper.
of course, I sprung for...
the artificial
buttery-flavored topping.
Nice touch. You know, I could
really make you into something.
What are you guys doing?
Uh, do you mind?
We're talking here.
Well, you can't be talking
to Shawn...
'cause Shawn told me
he can't talk to anybody.
Did you forget about
our basketball game?
Sorry, Cory, I guess
I lost track of the time.
Hang on a minute, Cory.
This is guy stuff, oK?
Basketball is guy stuff.
Ha ha!
They're so cute at this age.
All right, so you and Hilary...
are sitting
in the movie theater.
-What'd you go see?
-Like we watched the movie.
Don't tell me you--
Yes. We threw malt balls
at people's heads for two hours.
Well, not the way
I would've gone...
but, hey, you're still playing
in the minors.
You know, Shawn, there's
probably another solid hour...
of basketball light out there.
Come on. Let's go.
You know who I'm sitting
in the car with? Nobody.
Morgan,
can't we do this next week?
No. Mother's Day is Sunday,
and I need a present.
That's right.
I need to get one, too.
I've been racking my brain
real hard...
for a special gift for Mom.
oK, what do you want me
to pick up?
oh, whatever's laying around.
Move it, mall boy.
Let's go shoot some hoops.
Wouldn't you rather play
a little one-on-one with Hilary?
Come on, Cor.
Let's just go play.
No. You made it perfectly clear.
She throws malt balls
as well as I do.
You know what?
If you hold the malt ball...
in your mouth for a minute
right before you throw it...
it really sticks
in people's hair.
-Did Hilary teach you that?
-Yeah. She's majorly twisted.
oh, and suddenly I'm not?
Cory, what's the big deal?
It's always been you and me.
It's you and me now...
and it's going to be
you and me forever.
Nothing has changed.
I'm going to go sit with Hilary.
oh, yeah. Nothing's changed.
All right,
Shawn wants to be with a girl?
TWo can play at that game.
First stop--research.
Minkus, let's talk Perky.
Ah, your telegram
has finally arrived.
No, this isn't romance.
It's revenge.
TWo sides of the same hormone.
All right, bottom line--
what does that magazine
say you've got to do...
to get a girl
to go out with you?
Me? Almost nothing.
But you,
it's going to take some effort.
And you wonder why
you sit alone at lunch.
Here's your first dating tip.
Don't insult the boy
with the Perkys.
I'm sorry. All right,
so what do I have to do?
According to the survey
in the September issue...
what do you think
is the number one thing...
girls want from a guy?
Uh, loose change?
That's number nine.
The number one thing
is shared interest.
And that means...
Cory, this isn't algebra.
This is something
you can conceivably understand.
Shared interests. Talk to me.
If she's into something,
show an interest in it.
Example--
if the girl you're dating...
is interested in numismatics,
you talk about...
Numizmos?
Coins.
All right, give me
number two on that list...
just in case I can't fake
an interest in something.
-Sense of humor.
-No problem.
I'm a regular laugh riot.
All right, so how do l
select a lucky girl?
Well, just think of someone...
you're completely
comfortable with...
someone you could
share a meal with...
and someone who doesn't mind
having you around.
Well, my mom's already taken.
Cory, just go for
the first thing in a dress.
A dress. A dress.
-Topanga.
-Yes, Cory?
So, what's interesting
in your life right now?
Well,
Mercury is in retrograde...
making projects
difficult to complete...
and causing general chaos
in the universe.
You know, not only is that
unbelievably interesting...
it reminds me of a joke
I once heard.
How did the astrologer
cross the road?
-I don't know.
-ln his Taurus.
But I kid the zodiac.
Um, would you like to go...
to Bob Stubcheck's Burger World
after school?
Cory, I'm a vegetarian.
of course you are.
That's why we're just going
to meet at Burger World...
and walk over to
lnternational House of Salads.
I love lHOS.
Who doesn't?
oK. Gee, I wonder
what the sprout of the day is.
Who cares?
You can't go wrong...
with a nice bowl
of spaghetti and sprout balls.
So, I'll just meet you at 4:30.
oK, it's a date.
A date?
Who said anything about a date?
What have I done?
oK. What do you know
that I don't know?
Nothing.
-Which kid is it?
-Cory.
oh, I knew it.
oK, oK. Let's see.
He's too old to steal candy,
but too young to wreck a car.
oh, no. It's a girl.
It is.
Cory is going on his first date.
Isn't that sweet?
Yeah. Poor slob.
What are you saying?
You're his father.
You should be proud.
Hey, I've been
on the guy side of dating.
I mean, he's fine now, but he's
just a little step away from...
huh-huh-huh-huh-huh.
Dating was always fun for me.
I remember talking on the phone
to eight different guys a night.
Yeah, well,
the only way I survived it...
was knowing
that one day I'd be married...
and I'd be calling the shots.
Honey, I'm so sorry things
didn't work out for you.
I Wonder if
I can still Warn him...
about the minefield
he's about to step into...
without ruining his life.
Well, Cory doesn't appear
to be suffering like you did.
He's actually excited
about this date.
I overheard him telling Shawn...
that he couldn't
play basketball today...
because he was going out
with Topanga.
Topanga? Cory's always teasing,
making fun of her.
oh, no. This is bad.
Hi, Mom. Hi, Dad.
Cory, I think
this is so wonderful.
Son, this is the stupidest
thing you've ever done.
Before I shoot myself
in the foot...
which stupid thing
are we talking about?
-Your date with Topanga.
-What were you thinking?
Everything started
getting all fuzzy...
after that telegram movie.
Not the hormonal telegram.
Are they still showing
that film?
I cried during that movie.
If it wasn't for that movie,
I'd still be twelve.
Yeah, it had a weird effect
on a lot of people.
But ever since We saw it...
people are doing
really strange things.
Well, you certainly are. You've
never asked a girl out before.
Yeah, well, neither did Shawn.
Did you ask Topanga out
so you could keep up with him?
Whoa. That's weird.
How did she know?
It's the sorority of Satan.
Well, Cor, as much as
I wanted to see you...
go out
on your first little date...
I don't think
it's fair to Topanga.
As much as
I wanted to see it, too...
I--I think your mother's right.
You should cancel--now.
Mom, Dad, you're right.
With women,
honesty is the best policy.
And he thinks
he's ready to date.
Hi. Is Topanga there?
Yeah, I did mean physically.
Hi, Topanga.
It's me--Cory Matthews.
You probably remember me
from school.
Yeah. Well, listen,
when I made this date...
I didn't know it at that time,
but now I just found out.
Topanga, I got to be
totally honest with you.
[Coughs]
I got the flu,
and I can't go out.
I feel fine about that.
Fall-away jumper at the buzzer.
Good if it goes.
Three-pointer! Yes! Sixers win!
Whoo! Whoo!
[Knock on door]
Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! Whoo! Whoo!
Whoo! Whoo!
Whoo.
Hi, Cory. How are you feeling?
Uh, clammy. Very fluish. Yeah.
It's very contagious.
You better get out of here.
Here. Drink this.
It'll detoxify your aura.
-What is it?
-It's called bancha tea.
Smells like a bancha gym socks.
Cory, it's a remedy
that's been used for centuries.
"Best if used before
Lincoln's assassination."
I just wanted
to help you feel better.
I'm sorry if I bothered you.
Wait, Topanga. Thanks
for bringing the tea, but...
I don't need to drink it
'cause I'm not technically sick.
Then why did you say you were?
Well, I guess because
I didn't know how to tell you.
I'm not ready
to go out on a date yet.
That's oK. Jedidiah and Chloe
have always told me...
"Listen to your inner voice.
It'll let you know
what is true for you."
Yeah. My parents said that, too.
only they said it...
without all the planets
circling around their heads.
So I'll see you at school?
Yeah,
unless Feeny moves my seat.
Yeah.
Well, I guess I better be going.
And I guess
I'll be staying here.
May I ask you
a personal question?
Sure.
Why are there socks
all over your floor?
oh. I was just practicing.
I envy your athletic ability.
oh, this? It's not so hard.
Come on,
I'll give you some pointers.
All right.
First, you grab some ammo.
Ninja turtles?
And now they're gone.
Um, anyway, the key
is good color commentary.
If you can live up to
your own hype, you got it made.
Watch this.
Matthews sees an open lane.
He drives hard to the boards.
He leaps over Shaquille o'Neal,
kisses it off the glass!
It's good! He scores!
I could never do that.
Sure you can. Give it a try.
But I'm not familiar
with the terminology.
All right, I'll do the color.
You just worry about
getting the ball in the basket.
Topanga's triple-teamed
at the time line.
She breaks the trap,
heads to the top of the key...
and leaps toward the basket,
doing a spiraling tomahawk 360!
Slam dunk!
Look. We both made a basket.
Technically, yeah, but, uh...
basketball's so much more fun
when you actually move.
All right, you try
and make another basket...
and I'll try and block you.
Way to go, Topanga.
Huh-huh-huh-huh-huh.
Huh-huh-huh-huh.
It's nice that you help
your father with the laundry.
Yeah, well, we're
a fairly cutting-edge family...
so, uh, my mom does
most of the laundry.
I'm just helping out because
Mother's Day is coming up.
So you're doing chores
for your Mother's Day gift?
You think
I could get away with that?
What are you getting your mom?
I could use some ideas.
At our house,
we don't celebrate Mother's Day.
We feel it's merely
a commercial fabrication...
of the greeting card industry.
She has, however, asked
for a dust buster.
My mom's pretty well set
for small appliances...
and my funds
are sort of limited.
You don't need money. You just
need to use your right brain.
Wow. All these years
I've been using the wrong one.
So what do you think
I should get my mom?
You can never go wrong
with something from the heart.
Right or left heart?
You're killing me, Cory.
Huh-huh-huh-huh-huh.
-Hey, guys.
-There he is--young me.
How was your second date?
-You had another date?
-Yeah. My last one.
Ah, second-date slump. I've
seen it happen a thousand times.
Not to me.
You know, you know, I'm
thinking it's deeper than that.
See, each one of us is born with
a certain amount of coolness.
A guy like Minkus could live
to be a thousand years old...
and never use
a drop of his cool.
Me--
I'm a thirteen-year-old burnout.
Shawn, get a grip.
You're still cool.
It's just the planet Mercury
in retrospect.
What are you babbling about?
Some astrology thing.
Topanga was explaining it to me.
Hey, that's right.
How was your date?
What date? I didn't have a date.
I canceled it.
oh, come on, Cor.
When I got home from work...
you and Topanga were looking
pretty cozy on the couch there.
That Was not a date.
She just came over
to bring me some aura juice.
And?
And nothing. I taught her
how to shoot a basket.
oK, so let's recap. Point "A,"
she brought refreshments.
Point "B,"
you chose the activity.
Sounds like a date to me.
Read my lips--
there was no date.
We talked about
what we were getting our moms...
for Mother's Day.
Aha.
Point "C," shared interests.
Sixteen to base. We have
a confirmed date. Send backup.
Uh, Topanga?
You and l
have to get something straight.
Yes, Cory?
Friday night when
you came over to my house...
that was not a date.
I'm not into labels.
Yeah, but if you were...
what we had Friday night
would not be labeled a date...
'cause if you'll recall...
the circumstances
of that evening...
I canceled What Would have been
labeled a date.
That's fine, Cory.
It was not a date.
Well, I'll see you later.
oK.
Hey, Topanga?
You know, your idea about
writing my mom a poem...
for Mother's Day
really worked out great.
She cried.
Tears are the thank you notes
of the soul.
You know a lot about women.
Well, I am going to grow up
to be one.
Face it. Minkus was right.
Don't you hate it
when that happens?
No matter how you look at it...
there's going to be hormones,
and there's going to be girls.
Important girls are going
to come into our lives...
and stay for days at a time.
You know what's cool?
We made it through
our first dates...
and we're still best friends.
And we're going to stay
best friends...
through second dates,
proms, engagements, marriages.
Second marriages.
Whatever comes along...
we're going to stand here
and face it together...
shoulder to shoulder.
-Hi, Shawn.
-Hi, Cory.
-Later.
-Laterമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ