-Hi, Dad.
-Whoa, ho, ho.
What, baseball? In this storm?
I don't think so.
Dad, that's a drizzle.
[Thunder]
A thundery, stormy
kind of drizzle.
Mm-hmm. Forget it, wise guy.
Find something to do
around here.
I've been sitting inside
all day.
What am I supposed to do
for fun?
Have tea with your sister.
-I made red zinger.
-Yeah, zing this.
Somebody needs a nap.
My life bites--
boring, predictable...
never a surprise.
Don't turn on the lights.
Shawn?
The cops are after me,
maybe even the FBl.
You're not involved,
unless you want to be.
[Thunder]
I'm in!
[Theme music playing]
You can't tell anybody I'm here.
Right, right.
How'd you get in here, anyway?
I climbed up the tree
into your window.
I didn't want anyone to see me.
Cory, I'm a fugitive.
Fugitive? Cool! Give me details.
oK.
You remember that cherry bomb?
oh, no. Feeny found it.
You're suspended!
Nothing good ever happens to me.
All day I kept feeling it
in my pocket...
all round and waxy,
just begging me to light it.
I mean, I could actually
hear it saying...
"Light me. Light me, Shawn.
Blow something up."
Well, what did you blow up?
Well, I was riding my bike
down "K" Street--
You blew up "K" Street?
-I park at the Market Giant--
-You blew up the Market Giant?
That's my dad's store.
I have mixed feelings.
But there on the ground
by the shopping carts--
a matchbook.
It was like a sign, you know,
saying, "Now, Shawn.
Now. Let the sucker blow."
So you're holding
the lit cherry bomb--
I don't remember lighting it.
But suddenly
there it was in my hand...
sparks flying off the fuse...
and suddenly, I realized,
this thing's going to go off.
I mean, I could lose an eye,
lose an arm...
wind up looking like
our shop teacher.
So why didn't you just throw it?
There were people all around.
I could've hurt somebody.
I just knew I had to get it
far, far away, so I mailed it.
You blew up
a United States mailbox?
Well, it's still standing...
although the sides did puff out
like a fat guy burping.
All the stuff inside
got torched though.
You should have seen
the flames...
and the freaked-out look
on people's faces.
Why am I never around
when the great stuff happens?
I think I shook the cops.
What do I do now?
I can't go home.
Why not? It wasn't like
you did it on purpose.
Look, I did it.
That's the only part
my old man's going to hear.
I stepped over the line
this time, Cory.
I'm going to get killed
for this.
What are you going to do?
You think I could stay here
for a couple days...
just until I figure things out?
Fine with me.
I'll go ask my mom.
You're really new at this,
aren't you?
What?
No one can know I'm here,
especially not your folks.
They'll tell my mom and dad.
oh, right, right, right.
What about Eric?
He's dumb, but I think he'll
notice a third guy in the room.
I'll hide in the closet.
Have you seen my closet?
oK, under the bed.
oK, but you may not be the only
living thing under there.
Hi. How are you doing?
Jeez, how do you live like this?
MOTHER: Cory. dinner!
So what do you say? Can I stay?
of course you can.
Now get out of that wet stuff
and put on some of my clothes.
I'll sneak up some food.
Remember, I'm your accomplice.
I'm Accomplice Boy.
-Thanks a lot, man.
-No, thank you.
It's about time there's
a little excitement around here.
Listen. Listen, Cor.
You're going downstairs...
to keep something
from your parents...
and if it was me,
I wouldn't worry...
but I know you.
You're going to act weird.
Attempt to stay cool, huh?
Cool? Me? Ha!
They won't notice a thing.
Dad and Mom,
I have so much homework.
I'm going to eat in my room,
and I need fuel.
I need lots of fuel.
I need enough fuel for two...
although
there's only one of me...
which is so interesting,
don't you think?
Cory,
you're grounded for two weeks.
What did I do?
I don't know,
but the way you're behaving...
it's got to be
at least two weeks.
Dad, I can honestly tell you
I haven't done a thing.
[Thump]
What was that?
My homework fell off my desk.
There's so darn much of it.
Ha ha ha.
oK.
What are you, bowling up here?
Shawn?
I guess my pants
are a little short on you.
No, no, no, they fit great.
Anyone ever tell you
you're built like a chimp?
Did anybody ever tell you...
don't insult
the boy with the food?
No ketchup? I alWays have
ketchup on my meat loaf.
oh, you're absolutely right.
I'm going to go downstairs
right now...
and tell my mom that Shawn...
the cherry bomb
mailbox killer...
would like a little ketchup
on his meat loaf.
Fine, fine.
I'll eat this dry meat brick.
-oh, Cory!
-Hide!
Think you're pretty smooth,
don't you?
-I know what's going on.
-You do?
Uh-huh. Smuggling food, strange
noises, the smell in here.
Smell?
Yeah,
I tried the same thing once.
You're hiding a puppy, huh?
Where is he?
Come here, puppy.
Where's the cute little boy?
oh, it's a big puppy.
oK, Eric, you're right.
I'm hiding a puppy,
but I let it go.
-When?
-Uh, just a minute ago.
-You let the puppy go?
-Uh-huh.
out a second story window?
What was I thinking?
Hey, guys.
Mom, where are you going?
It's time for Morgan's bath...
and her door to the bathroom
is locked.
Wait a minute.
Let me get this straight.
[Shouting] You're going
into the bathroom...
to give Morgan a bath?
Nothing gets past you.
Hey, Cor?
Lassie came home.
I can explain What he's doing.
No, no, no.
Look, I don't even want to know.
I mean, if I know the truth...
I only have to lie
when questioned.
I don't want to know anything
about you two.
Let's just cut to my bribe,
shall we?
Dry brick of meat?
Yeah, that's tempting...
but I was thinking,
oh, I don't know...
you two take over
all my household chores?
In the bizarro World.
Eric,
I don't even do my own chores.
FATHER: Cory! Eric!
Trash night. Whose turn
is it to take out the cans?
You know, Dad, an interesting
thing. See, we were just--
oh, no! My turn, right?
oh. Hey, thanks.
I think Shawn was making
a daring political statement.
And what statement was that,
build more prisons?
You guys don't know
anything about it.
Sorry I'm late.
I see you've all heard...
about Mr. Hunter's little stunt
yesterday.
I just spoke with his parents.
Evidently, Shawn
didn't come home last night.
I imagine no one here
has heard from him.
Me?
What makes you think
I heard from Shawn?
I was addressing
the entire class.
Yeah,
but you make it sound like...
I lit the cherry bomb
and stuck it in the mailbox...
on "K" Street
near the Market Giant.
I'm guessing.
He claims he hasn't spoken
with Shawn since the incident...
yet he knows
the precise location...
knows Hunter's plot
involved a cherry bomb.
I smell conspiracy.
I smell cover-up.
I smell a nerd
with nine fingers.
Mr. Matthews,
unhand that Minkus.
Mr. Minkus, return to your seat.
Now, then, we shall continue
reading aloud from page 1 57.
Edgar Allan Poe's
The Tell-tale Heart.
"They heard.
They suspected."
"They knew."
[Heartbeat, thunder]
"I couLd bear those
hypocriticaL smiLes no Longer.
"I feLt
that I must scream or die...
"and now. hark. again.
"Louder. Louder.
Louder. "
Mr. Matthews? Anything wrong?
&  You made me Love you &
&  I didn't wanna do it &
SHAWN: Ow.
&  You made me want you &
I checked outside the store.
I didn't see it anywhere.
-See what?
-Uh, it.
It?
It--ltaly.
I didn't see ltaly.
I didn't see France.
I didn't see
anybody's underpants.
Well, consider yourself lucky.
I just did the laundry.
And while
I was putting it away...
I discovered a little something
you've been hiding.
[Heartbeat]
What?
You organized your closet.
oh, yeah, yeah.
Practically cleaned itself.
So why don't you just
give me a hug and move along?
oK. I'll just leave you here
all by yourself.
Bye.
In the last twenty-four hours...
I almost blow off my hand
and get sucked into a Hoover.
You organized my closet?
Yeah, well, I didn't mean to.
Just what was I supposed to do
in this room all day?
Let me tell you, you have...
a very up-to-date collection
of video games.
I especially enjoyed Pong.
Feeny said
your parents came by school.
You didn't say anything,
did you?
Well, he was working me,
all right, but I was a stone.
-Cory!
-Yeah! I'm alone! Hide.
I fear for my life.
Hey. How was your day?
Quit pumping me! I know nothing!
Well, me--I had a lousy day.
You see, yesterday
I put about, oh...
twenty-six bills in the mailbox
outside my store, and...
today I found out that, uh--
Well, you know the rest.
Yeah, I heard something
along the lines...
of a mailbox natural disaster.
You know, the glue on those
stamps is highly flammable.
I heard that Shawn
may be involved...
to the extent
that, um, he did it.
Huh. Nowthat I did not hear.
SHAWN: Ah-choo!
-Bless you.
-Thank you.
You know,
when I was growing up...
there was a kid
in my neighborhood...
who was a lot like Shawn--
always getting into trouble.
You know,
small things at first--
shoplifting candy,
letting air out of tires...
but pretty soon,
he got kind of bored...
moved on to more serious stuff,
more dangerous.
Dad, Shawn's not like that.
I don't know. I think he is.
And if he were here right now,
I'd come down on him very hard.
SHAWN: Uh!
Uh, that meat loaf.
Because what Shawn did
was irresponsible and dumb.
How come you're telling me this?
Because you need to know that
if you ever do anything wrong...
you can always come home.
I don't care how bad it is...
it can never be as bad
as not coming home.
You don't have to worry
about me, Dad. I'm a come-homer.
Fine, because I don't care
how tight a spot you're in...
SHAWN: Ooh!
we're here for you.
-Deal?
-Deal.
oh, man.
Your dad really hurt me.
That stuff he said?
No. He sat on my head.
You know, Shawn...
I bet ifWe explained to my dad
how this happened...
he could talk to your dad,
and then--
No way.
I can't ever go home, Cory.
Didn't you hear
what my dad was saying?
Not all of it.
I blacked out a couple times.
All I'm saying is...
I think that if
both our dads worked together...
and talked it over, and my dad
explained to your dad...
-that you're still an oK kid--
-lt won't work, Cor.
Why not?
Because my dad will kill
your dad just to get to me.
Shawn, you're overreacting.
Cory, all our lives we've done
these little things...
but we've always stayed
on this side of the line.
What line?
The line that separates
the little bad...
from the big bad--
the line I blow up
with my cherry bomb.
Shawn, you're wrong.
Watch. I'll prove it to you.
Dad?
Dad, can you come here a second?
-No! Cory!
-Dad?
All right, my dad's coming.
He'll fix everything.
Shawn?
Shawn!
Hey, Hunter!
oK, he's gone.
You think he's going home?
I think
everything's going to be oK.
-Know why?
-Why?
Well, because that talk
you gave me up in my room--
well, you didn't know it,
but Shawn heard the whole thing.
Really?
Yeah, he was under my bed.
-Under your bed?
-Not the one I sat on?
Actually, I've been
hiding Shawn up there...
since yesterday afternoon.
-How long have you known?
-Since yesterday afternoon.
The noises
coming from your room.
The food you snuck upstairs.
It could've been a puppy.
Cory, no one is that naive.
Uh, I happen to like
the puppy theory.
Mr. Feeny saw Shawn
sneak in yesterday...
and he phoned us to let us know.
It's a conspiracy...
an international
adults' hot line.
Any kid anywhere makes a move--
the phones are ringing.
Wait. You guys didn't tell
Shawn's parents, did you?
of course we did.
Cory, didn't you think...
how scared Shawn's parents
would be...
not knowing where their son was?
Wait, I don't get it.
If you guys knew all along,
why didn't you bust us?
Sure would've been easier on me.
It was killing me
trying to hide this from you.
Well, we knew he was safe here
with his best friend...
who we hoped would help him
make the right decision...
and go home.
Cor,
I know you really like Shawn.
I mean,
he's been your best bud...
since he taught you how to pick
the lock on your playpen...
but there's something I think
you should know about him.
You think he's a criminal.
I think he has rough edges.
I think
he's at a point in his life...
where he can go one of two ways.
Back on my side of the line...
or gone forever
into cherry bomb land.
Cory, Shawn
has always reminded your dad...
of someone he knew
when he was a kid.
You had a best friend
like Shawn?
Uh-uh. I was like Shawn.
I had a best friend like you.
-You did?
-Mm-hmm.
And when I was
about twelve years old...
I got into trouble once,
and I considered my options--
I could hop a train
to California.
I could start my life
at thirteen...
get a job at fourteen,
be married at fifteen...
have kids at sixteen.
I thought it was a great idea.
Sounds like a dumb idea to me.
oh, you think so, huh?
Yeah. Just because
you make one little mistake...
you don't want
to throw your whole life away.
You see, guys like you
and my best friend Richie--
that's the way you think.
Guys like me and Shawn--
we don't think like that.
-Did you ever go to California?
-No.
-Well, what happened?
-I don't know.
Somehow I ended up here
in a room with you.
Listen, Shawn's going
to get in touch with you.
What should I do when he does?
A kid like you--you'll know.
Well, I guess the room is empty.
What a perfect time
to set fire to my desk.
What, Cory told you I was here?
Did he rat on me?
on the contrary, Mr. Matthews
has been a true and loyal ally.
If anybody has betrayed
this friendship...
it was you the moment
you asked him to lie.
I would have done the same
for him.
Mr. Feeny, about the only thing
I'm not worried about...
in my life right now
is Cory and my friendship.
oh, here we go.
I knew it was here somewhere.
In my eagerness
to depart for the weekend...
I forgot to take it home.
What is it?
Canvas.
I often paint on the weekends.
Very strong material.
Difficult to rip.
Give it a try.
Go on.
Uh-huh.
of course, rugged as it is...
even the smallest snip...
and...
You see, Mr. Hunter...
once the integrity
has been breached...
even the strongest fabric
can unravel.
Even the strongest friendship.
Yeah, well, here.
Have a bandanna.
Aren't you going to turn me in?
Uh, no, I don't think I have to.
oh. It's not Monday?
All week long, you two ache
to get out of this classroom...
and here you are
in the middle of the night...
sneaking into it.
Did you bring the stuff
I asked for?
It's empty.
How about some money?
Can I borrow your bike?
Actually, I got a ride here.
-Who from?
-Your mom and dad.
-They're here?
-They're parked outside.
Forget it. I'm not going home.
You don't want to help me,
that's fine.
I'll sneak out the back.
Get out of my way, Cory, or--
or else what, you'll hit me?
Fine. Go ahead.
Wipe the floor with me.
-Cory, just get out of my way.
-No.
You have to go home, Shawn.
You can't run away.
Yes, I can!
Just get away from the door.
Shawn.
I'm not moving.
Cory, what do you want from me?
I want you to come back
on my side of the line.
How am I supposed to do that?
Just go home.
My parents are going
to ground me for, like, a year.
Well, then,
I'll see you in a year.
Man, I'm going to get so killed.
Yeah, well, we're only twelve.
We live again.
[Knock on door]
-What day is it?
-The 19th.
It's Shawn!
-Aah!
I'm free!
-Ha!
&  Doo doo doo doo do &
A whole month! How are you?
oh, not too bad.
My eyes are still trying
to adjust to the light though.
Are you hungry?
Nah, they gave me bugs
with my potato today.
Whoa! I hate to interrupt
your touching reunion...
but there's one minute left
in triple overtime.
Come on, Mom,
you got to see this.
oK, I've got five more numbers
to enter...
on this spreadsheet,
and then I am done.
oh, TV. Hi.
Dawn, I know I've asked you out,
like, fifty times...
and I know you said no,
but you got to respect
my willingness to get shot down.
You will? Right now?
oK, where should I meet you?
-What happened?
-I had her!
-The game!
-Barbie's hair!
-I didn't save!
-Dad, what happened?
MOTHER: ALan. didn't you pay
the eLectric biLL?
ALAN: Of course I paid it.
A month ago.
I put it in the maiLbox
right outside my store.
MOTHER: On cherry bomb day?
SHAWN: Good night, everybodyഡഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ