Tonight is going to be
the best night of our lives.
Mom and Dad--gone.
Your brother--date.
Who's left in charge?
Judy--queen of zits.
We'll tell her she's looking...
especially broken out
this evening...
So she'll spend all night...
in the bathroom
squeezing her face...
Leaving us free to watch...
Barney SaLutes the ALphabet?
That's just the box.
It's parent camouflage.
outside, a happy purple sock.
Inside, the guts are flying.
Whoa!
I'm BLowing Up
Your Head. Part 6--
Stumpy's Revenge.
I thought Stumpy died
in Part 5.
Well, that's why
he wants revenge.
Cool.
[Theme music playing]
ERlC: ooh,
"Barney Does the ABCs."
You know, I don't want
to ruin the ending...
for you, Cor,
but, uh..."Z."
You totally underestimate me.
open it.
Ha.
Stumpy's Revenge.
Not bad for a baby scam.
This is not a baby scam.
This is a totally major scam.
"Stumpy's Revenge"
is rated "R" For violence.
Yeah, maybe a little nudity?
Yeah, but we can
fast forward over that.
All right, you're right.
It's a major scam.
But hey, if you're
gonna do the crime...
be sure you're ready
to do the time.
What do you mean?
Why do you think
Mom and Dad...
are letting me go get
my driver's license...
with Jason and his brother
instead of with them?
Because they hope you'll
get lost and never come back?
No. Because they trust me.
See, I've spent my whole life...
putting deposits
in the trust bank...
and today I'm cashing in.
What trust bank?
You get busted all the time.
Just a few,
carefully selected times.
Enough so Mom and Dad think
they're doing their job.
See, they know
if something major happens...
I'll come to them.
Wow. I never thought
I'd say this...
but I could learn from you.
And maybe I can fit
into this master plan of yours.
After you get your license...
we could drive downtown
and check out...
that new baseball card shop
on Third Street.
Excellent!
Yes! Then we could
go to the drive-thru...
and pick up
a bucket of hot wings...
for me and Shawn to eat
with the movie.
-oh, yes!
-Yes! Yes!
That's why
I'm getting my license.
So I could bring
my little brother...
to all the places
he's ever wanted to go to.
Unless Jason and l
have a date...
with two totally major babes.
oh, wait, we do.
But here's
a lovely parting gift.
[Dog barking]
You doing your homework?
Mm-hmm.
It's still light outside.
What's going on?
I'm being responsible.
No, really. What's going on?
Ta-da!
What do you think?
Uh...
Danger! Danger, Will Robinson!
What's the problem?
Clean shirt,
new jeans, jacket.
I look good.
Alan, tonight is
really important to me.
All the real estate biggies
in Pennsylvania...
are gonna be there...
and they're kind of
a non-casual bunch.
How dressed up do you have
to be to be bored to death?
Put on a suit.
If you die of boredom...
then I won't have to change
your clothes for your funeral.
Can't I just stay home...
spend some quality time
with my kids, huh?
No! I mean, you don't want
to let Mom down, right?
oh, come on, son.
How does a night of bonding...
with your dear old dad sound?
Pretty good, huh?
Great, yeah.
It sounds great.
So I'll meet you halfway.
You go with Mom...
and I'll miss
the heck out of you.
I am so proud
to be the best friend...
of the first guy
in history...
to fail his driver's test
before it started!
The DMV guy waved me forward.
I pulled up, like, two inches.
That was not the DMV guy.
That was the father
of the kid ahead of you.
How am I supposed to know that?
I'm at the DMV.
I assume the guy...
waving me forward
is the DMV Guy.
Eric, DMV guys are cops, oK?
They don't usually wave
you forward with a can of beer.
[Telephone rings]
Hello?
oh, hey, Tracy.
Yeah, there's some bad news.
Um, I went--
Tracy, how you doing?
Bad news? oh, uh...
the cash machine only gave us
200 bucks for tonight's date.
oh, you, uh...
you bought a new dress?
oh, you hope
it's not too short.
Sweetheart,
life can be too short...
But dresses, no.
Heh heh heh heh.
I'll pick you up
tonight at 8:00.
What are you saying to her?
We cannot pick them up...
until I take the driving test
again in two weeks.
oK, that's just logic.
That's getting in our way.
Look...
Ahem.
Hey, looking good, Mr. M.
Hey, guys.
Hey, how's the road warrior?
Dad, look, about the--
He got off to kind of
a rocky start...
but, you know,
once he had his foot...
on the accelerator,
next thing you knew...
it Was over. Ha ha.
Attaboy! I knew you wouldn't
let me down.
Nope. No letting down here.
Not the father,
not the friend...
and not two lovely babes
in drafty apparel.
Jason, I have to tell him.
Yes, you do.
That is the right thing to do.
And tomorrow is
the right day to do it.
Ahem.
Rrrr.
ow!
Whoo!
Too young to be a mom.
Too pretty to be
in real estate.
Why are you sucking
up to my mom?
Hey, have you seen my mom?
You know, son,
I was thinking...
somebody in this house
should have a good time tonight.
Those are your car keys.
Mm-hmm.
-Dad, l--
-Eric, Eric, his car keys.
Your father is giving you
his car keys.
You know, someday I hope
I can be half the man you are.
Well, right now you are.
No leaving this house
until Judy gets here.
[Door closes]
I am not lying to my parents.
I mean, they trust me.
They gave me life.
They deserve better from me.
oK, you got that
out of your system?
Yeah. What's the plan?
You are gonna drive us
on the date.
[Telephone rings]
Hello? oh, hi, Judy.
Yeah. How are you?
What? You can't.
You can't.
She did.
-Did what?
-She bailed.
She's not gonna babysit
tonight. We're dead.
No, we're not dead.
All's we have to do...
is find another babysitter.
Where are we gonna find
another babysitter...
on fifteen minutes notice?
[Sighs]
Mr. Feeny.
Hello, Eric.
I was wondering
if you could help me out...
with a problem I've got.
Always happy to assist
a former student.
See, our babysitter
canceled, so...
Judy Horn?
Yeah. Some kind of
a skin crisis.
I don't even want to think about
what a crisis for her would be.
Her whole head
would have to pop.
Uh, anyway,
I'm going...
to a classical music
concert with a friend--
You? Classical music?
Beethoven or Prokofiev?
Uh, Beethoven.
Symphony or concerto?
Uh, symphony.
Blonde or brunette?
Blondes--
Brahms.
Ah, so the real
situation is...
that you have a date,
but you can't go...
until you find
a replacement babysitter.
Within the next ten minutes.
oh, well, you have quite
a time crunch, don't you?
Name your price.
Manual labor--
spreading manure in my yard
for the next...four sundays.
Two sundays.
-Five.
-Done.
Yes, I would love another cup
of tea, thank you.
And would you like
to try on my new floppy hat?
No, Morgan.
Now, here I really must
draw the line.
I will not put on
your floppy hat.
Now, that's not going to work.
We had an agreement.
I was to get dressed up
and come to your tea party.
And then you were to leave me
in complete peace...
so that I could
grade my papers.
Now, I have upheld
my part of the bargain.
I have festooned myself...
in costume jewelry.
I have swilled your faux tea.
Now, I insist that you keep
your end of the bargain.
[Crying]
oh, all right. All right.
Give me the hat.
Happy now?
Uh-huh.
[Bell dings]
What's that?
My mix-and-bake cake
is ready.
oh, well.
I rush on winged feet.
[Click]
MAN ON Tv:....So.
aLL previous theories...
of the migratory pattern
of the Arctic caribou...
are shattered by
the startLing discovery...
that not one.
but two arctic caribou here...
where there were previousLy
not one. but none.
[Click]
MAN ON Tv:. ALL right.
coLLege girL in the shower...
kiss your head goodbye.
WOMAN ON Tv:.
No! Stumpy! No!
[ExpLosion]
Why did Stumpy
just blow up her head?
Well, that's a tough one, Cor.
Stumpy's a pretty complex guy.
Here We are.
MAN ON Tv:. After the infant
caribou is deLivered...
the mother Licks it free
of the birth fluids.
-Eww!.
oh, buck up. You're watching
the glorious tapestry of nature.
MAN ON Tv:. ALL right.
buxom night nurse.
Say hasta La vista
to your head.
WOMAN ON Tv:.
No. Stumpy!
Not the crossbow!
No!
[Bowstring shoots]
-Whoa!
ooh, she blowed up real good.
Bean dip?
Wonder if Eric's having
as good a time as we are.
Are you kidding?
Having fun is what he's best at.
Please give me back
my daddy's car.
There has to be some shred
of humanity in you.
What does that mean,
uh, humanity?
[Music playing]
[Growls]
All right.
Mr. Feeny will be here
in a few minutes.
Now, um, excuse me, mister--sir,
I still don't understand...
why you can't give us the car.
I mean, we have the money.
oh, so I should just
hand over a vehicle...
to any yutz
who has forty bucks.
You want the car,
then I need to see...
the address
on your driver's license...
matches the address
on your vehicle registration.
Then...I'm happy.
Make me happy.
I got a junior with a Camaro.
Should we take it?
Anything to get out of here.
You know, I really
learned a lot tonight.
Like What?
White curb good, red curb bad?
No, I learned
that girls like you...
are only interested
in using people.
And you know something?
We're glad you found...
a junior with a Camaro,
because we don't need you.
They think they don't need us.
Poor naive lambs.
[Both laugh]
Tony with a "Y '," huh?
That's cool.
It was my mother's idea.
So, uh, what can I do
for you girls?
our friend left
his license at home.
And we know
you're not supposed to...
But we thought maybe you could
give him his car anyway.
our moms would be so worried
if we're not home by curfew.
So, you'll just be needing
the one car?
[Both laugh]
Yep, just one
little itty-bitty car.
But we may be back,
Tony with a "Y '."
Well, uh, here. You give this
to Vinnie at the impound lot...
and, uh,
he'll give you the car.
That was amazing.
You girls are unbelievable.
Yeah, we are.
Wait a minute. Aren't these
the guys who don't need us?
Yeah, well, then I guess
they can get back...
their pathetic dad-mobile
all by themselves.
-No!
No!
Tape! Tape!
[Horn honks]
Sounds like a Camaro.
oh, Mr. Feeny.
I never thought
I'd be happy to see you.
I wish I could say the same.
What seems to be the problem?
Dad's car got towed.
And we can't get it back
from Sasquatch.
oh, I'll clear this up
in no time.
Excuse me, young man.
It's, uh, Tony with a "Y '."
Fine, Tony. Might I inquire
why you won't release the car?
It's like I told the kid--
you ain't got a license,
you ain't getting the car.
Aren't.
What?
You aren't getting the car.
Wrong, pal.
I already got the car.
No, no.
You misunderstand me.
I was simply correcting
your grammar.
I don't need talking lessons...
from a guy
who's wearing an earring.
Could we get back
to the car issue, please?
The issue is, no license,
no car. Capisce?
Eric, why don't you just give
the man your driver's license?
Because l, uh...
I don't have it.
Well, tell me where you left it,
and I'll go get it.
Ahem. Well, I don't,
uh, technically...
Iike, at this
actual point in time--
He doesn't have a license.
He's got to.
Not even my brother's
that big an idiot.
I, uh...
beg to differ.
Missy...
brush your teeth
and go to bed.
You suck that lip back in.
Upstairs. Now.
You, return
to your home...now.
Jason, you cannot leave me
holding the bag for all this.
Ha ha ha. See how
little you know me?
And as for you, young man,
I want you to go to your room...
and wait till
your parents return.
Just because you were once
my sixth grade teacher...
does not give you the right
to tell me what to do.
Go to your room!
Apparently it does.
I don't suppose
your parents have any Maalox...
in the house, do they?
What are you watching?
Uh...
uh...
it's caribou...migrating
and licking their babies.
Where's the remote?
MAN ON Tv:. ALL right.
fun-Loving stewardess...
coffee. tea...
or bazooka sheLL?
WOMAN ON Tv:.
Uh...coffee?
No!
[ExpLosion]
ooh!
[Screaming]
Why did that man
just blow up her head?
-Uh, it's nature.
-It's human nature.
A rich tapestry
of exploding heads.
[Screams and expLosions]
That is cheap garbage.
Wait. What are you doing?
No, Mr. Feeny.
our machine's kind of tricky.
No!
This is rated "R."
Yeah, "R" for wrecked.
Now Shawn's gonna
have to pay for it.
-Shawn?
-Hey, you rented it.
AMY: George.
you're not supposed to be here.
What's wrong?
The babysitter canceled.
I'm doing my best to fill in.
He killed our tape.
What tape?
Good move.
Uh, tape? There is no tape.
Did I say tape?
What was I thinking?
You were thinking...
"Good night, Shawn."
Shawn, you cannot leave me here
with this tape.
Heh. See how little you know me?
I'm BLowing Up
Your Head. Part 6?
From the little I saw--
Uh, no. No, thank you, George.
I think I can figure out
the subtle plot nuances.
You smuggled a violent
"R"-rated movie into this house?
oh, no, no, honey.
Calm down.
This may look like
a violent film...
but at its heart,
it's really a morality tale...
about an eleven-year-old boy...
who's in terrible, terrible,
terrible trouble.
Dad, it's just a tape.
It's trash.
I don't Want it in the house.
Go to your room, Cory.
For how long?
31 years.
Mom, I'm your son.
Cory, you're dog meat.
Uh, Mom, Dad.
Speaking of Puppy Chow...
Wait a minute.
You're not here.
My car isn't in the driveway.
You're out driving it somewhere
very, very carefully, right?
Uh, Dad, I hope
you're in a good mood.
You lose.
Ahem. Uh,
your car got towed away.
You are the worst babysitter
that ever lived.
And your children
are the spawn of Satan.
Honey, I think
you should stay calm.
I am calm.
Under the circumstances,
I'm the Dalai stinking Lama.
Eric, where is the car?
It's at the impound station.
I have the forty bucks
to bail it out.
Great, but I'll have
to drive you down there...
So we can get it home.
Actually, you both
will have to drive him.
Why?
Because one of you is gonna have
to drive Mom's car back...
and one of you is gonna
have to drive your car back.
Why?
He hasn't got
a driver's license.
Well...
my work is done.
I'll just leave.
Tip?
No?
Well, then, all right.
I, uh...
I sort of failed
my driving test.
But you still decided to...
sort of drive my car...
without a license.
Well, you're going
to get your license.
And then I'm going
to take it away.
You are gonna be a pedestrian
for life, pal.
Go to your room, Eric.
No, I'm not finished
with him yet.
I haven't started
But I want to talk
with you now.
Is my authority
being undermined?
Would I do that
in front of your son?
Go to your room.
-No good.
-What, no good?
Who drives Morgan
to gym class?
Who drives Cory
to little league?
Who drives Eric
on a tristate search...
for the perfect
flannel shirt? Me.
I take these kids everywhere.
I help...
when I can.
I mean Well.
I want Eric
to get his license.
I have been waiting for this
for sixteen years.
So how are we supposed
to punish him?
Look, Eric sees driving...
as nothing but dates
with cheerleaders...
open road, unlimited freedom.
But I am seeing
his driving...
as trips to the dry cleaners
and the supermarket...
and taking
his brother and sister...
wherever they want to go.
I never should've
tried to scam them.
Crime doesn't pay.
Violence is bad.
They're gonna kill me.
Cor, just be happy
it was a baby scam.
Mine, on the other hand,
was a megascam...
a hyperscam,
the mother of all scams.
I am truly a dead man.
These could be our last few
precious moments together.
Is there anything
you want to say to me?
Yeah.
Here's a lovely parting gift.
ooh!
-Cory...
-Eric...
Dad...
Mom...
I think you know why we're here.
And I think you know
why we're here.
This is the sentencing phase
of the proceedings.
I'm the oldest.
Do me first.
Both of you are grounded
for two weeks.
BoTH: Aah! Two weeks?
Grounded?
That's horrible!
There's more.
BOTH: There's more.
During those two weeks,
you will do nothing but study...
the Pennsylvania
Motor Vehicle handbook...
and you will pass
your driver's test.
I'll try.
You'll pass.
I'll pass.
And what will I do
for two weeks?
oh, you're going
to watch TV.
Cool.
Educational TV, and nothing but
educational TV...
starting right now.
MAN ON Tv:. The caribou
marks its territory...
by defecating
and flinging its dung.
Eww!.
Come on, I'll be
late for gymnastics.
Eric, come on. Little league
starts in twenty minutes...
and we have to stop
at the cleaners...
to pick up my uniform.
I want to stop
for frozen yogurt.
And we have to pick up Shawn
and we have to stop...
and get pizza
because you're the snack mom.
How shall I spend
my afternoon?
Should I read magazines
and then soak in the tub...
or should I soak
and then read?
Soak and read,
read and soak.
Hi, hon.
How was your day?
Ahh, bliss.
It's good to have
a son who drives.
-Little league!
-Frozen yogurt!
I'll drive off a bridge,
I swear I will.
Take your mother's carമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ