Good morning, pumpkin.
I've been up since 6:00!
Nice mess.
It's my biggest.
Friday. I love Friday.
Soon I'm gonna be home
for the whole weekend.
Friday. I hate Friday.
Soon you're gonna be home
for the whole weekend.
-oh, you love me.
-oh, you wish.
Ahh, good morning.
Let me give you
a weekend weather update.
Whether or not I have a date
with Cindy this weekend...
depends on how partly cool
I am in school today.
There is a definite Vicki front
moving in this Saturday...
and temperatures
are expected to rise.
Cooling off by 10:00,
when you're expected to be home.
oh, Mom, we both know...
how unpredictable
the weather can be.
Don't mess With Mother Nature.
I'll be home by 10:00.
Hey, Mom,
where's my blue sugar moons?
Where's my marshmallow
teddy bears?
This cereal's bogus.
It's full of hamster food
and corn flake dust.
Where's all the good stuff?
Morgan?
She took out
all the good stuff.
I've been up since 6:00!
Morgan, all this is
is sugar-coated...sugar.
I'm feeling very perky.
Why don't we go up
to your room, honey?
How come? How come? How come?
How come? How come?
Because if we leave
right away...
we might make it to your bed
before the coma.
Coma? Coma?
Coma, coma, coma.
I've been up since 6:00!
Can't hold your sugar,
you shouldn't do breakfast.
Don't waste this, honey.
Have her paint the house.
Hey, Dad.
Good morning, Cory.
Hi, Eric.
Hello, Brooks Robinson
deep pocket...
Fielder's Choice model.
How are you feeling today,
all warm and broken in?
You know, Dad,
most people put their gloves...
under the mattress
to break them in.
Well, most people
don't have a glove...
that they broke in
25 years ago, Eric.
See, now, with this baby,
you baste it with Glovolium...
and you bake it
in a slow oven...
till the web's ready to
snap shut on any line drive...
that comes near
third base tomorrow.
The father/son softball game.
Has it been a year already?
Can you believe it?
-Uh-uh.
-No.
Who are you playing
this year, Dad?
Me? It's not about
me playing. It's us.
The game's nothing
without you guys.
Hey, that's nice.
Isn't that nice?
Yeah, that's nice.
You'll be thrilled
to know...
that the Market Giant Juggernaut
is gonna steamroll...
over the Unicorn
Rainbow Bookstore.
What, that new-age place?
Yeah. Why don't they
just give us the trophy?
I mean, these guys are
much too zen for baseball.
I mean, these are people
with inner peace...
and spiritual tranquillity.
Let's kill 'em.
The father/son softball game.
Has it been a year already?
Can you believe it?
-Uh-uh.
-No.
[Theme music playing]
ALL: And to the republic
for which it stands...
one nation, under God...
indivisible...
with liberty
and justice for all.
Miss Lawrence,
I couldn't help noticing...
that you didn't recite
the Pledge of Allegiance...
this morning.
Yes, sir. I elected not to.
Why was that?
I didn't feel like it.
This is gonna be cool.
What was that,
Mr. Matthews?
Uh, I said, this is
gonna be cool, Mr. Feeny.
Why?
'Cause you're finally gonna
nail Topanga for being weird.
Do you think it's weird
to engage in social protest?
I think it's weird
to pick on me...
when she didn't say
the pledge of allegiance.
Well, Mr. Matthews...
it seems that
you and Miss Lawrence...
have opposing positions
for this morning's debate.
Uh-oh.
You been set up, bud.
Mr. Feeny told you
not to say the pledge?
ohh.
Today's social studies
discussions--
American traditions...
the Pledge of Allegiance
versus social protest.
Mr. Matthews,
defend old Glory.
Miss Lawrence,
defend the right to dissent.
Just because it's a tradition
doesn't mean you have to do it.
But it's the Pledge
of Allegiance.
It takes, like,
ten seconds to say.
Why can't you just say it
and make everyone happy?
Because if I'm forced
to do it just because...
it's some tradition
I don't understand...
then it doesn't
make me happy.
Can you spell...
peculiar?
oh, and you're normal?
You talk to a flag
every day...
and you don't even know
what you're saying.
But I do it.
I do it because
I'm supposed to do it.
And that's what makes me
a great American.
[Humming
"Glory, Glory, Hallelujah"]
That's what makes
this country great.
That flag.
Because that flag
gives us the right...
to have this discussion.
And this discussion is the most
important discussion...
we will ever have, and--
[Bell rings]
out of here!
Parents don't understand...
how important
the weekend is, you know?
Yeah. Like there's not
enough pressure on us...
being in the sixth grade
all week.
And then they want us to
do stuff on our only days off.
only three days till Monday.
Minkus, I'm sure that if
you check your ticket stub...
you'll see that your seat
is in the goon section.
I'm just leaving my tray here
while I get an apple, oK?
I mean, my weekends
are jam-packed.
I have no spare time.
Minkus left
his hamburger here.
I get up saturday morning
and I watch "X-Men."
It's very hard for me to be
alone with Minkus's hamburger.
My next stop
is the comic book store.
Especially when
it's just sitting there...
begging for more salt.
Then in the afternoon,
I hang with you.
I don't know if this is...
a personality disorder
with me or what.
Then it's home for
Saturday night pizza night.
But I'm just never happy unless
I'm doing stuff like this.
And then it's four hours
of video games...
and it's a good night.
I don't mean
just a little happy.
Where's a spare minute?
I mean I'll have this moment
and know it was a good day.
I can't take the pressure
of a father/son softball game.
oh, I hate those.
They take it so seriously.
I know. My dad
always screams and yells...
Iike it's the most important
thing in the world.
And they always get injured.
To us it's only a game.
To them it's a guest shot
on "Rescue 91 1."
The trouble With fathers is...
they sometimes try
to live vicariously...
through their children.
oK, Minkus.
That's enough quality time.
Take your little hamburger
and go to your table.
Hey, did you do anything
to my hamburger?
Yeah. Sure.
Like doing something to his
hamburger gives me my jollies.
Look, guys.
Shaquille o'Neal.
BoTH: ooh, where?
Gee, I guess
we just missed him.
Hey, Minkus,
isn't that Stephen Hawking?
Where?
oh, darn. I missed him, too.
Well, see ya.
Why do they think
he's so much smarter than us?
Because he is, isn't he?
He's out there
practicing for tomorrow.
-We're trapped.
-What are we gonna do?
There's no way out.
MOM: Out of what?
That's Mom.
Yes, it is.
We're gonna have
to tell her.
Yes, we are.
Mom, we don't want to play
in the father/son softball game.
Why is this my problem?
Look, I think what
my-less-than-tactful...
Iittle brother
is trying to say...
is that these father/son
softball games are...
Not real exciting for you.
-Right.
So you understand
what we're saying.
I understand that
neither one of you...
is willing to give up a couple
of hours on a Saturday...
For something your father's
really looking forward to doing.
I'm really looking forward
to my date with Vicki tomorrow.
I mean, why should
I give that up?
Hey, Mom,
why don't you play?
Yeah.
Look, if this was
a husband/wife softball game...
believe me, I'd be there.
But it's not, thank God.
It's a father/son game.
Look, we're just asking you
to get us off the hook.
No. This is your hook...
and you're gonna hang on it
like the worms you are.
Mom, you're not walking out
on us for good, are you?
I'm going to the bank.
Your heartless father...
asked me to deposit
his paycheck...
so we could pay the bills.
oh, the nerve.
Where are you going?
I want to go with you.
No, honey. There's
long lines at the bank...
and there's
no place to sit.
It'd be a lot easier for me
and more fun for you...
if you stayed here
and played with your toys.
I'm going to the bank
with Mommy.
oK, Eric. You're older.
I'm counting on you
to get us out of this.
-I can do it.
-I know you can.
-I've got it.
-I knew you could!
Look, it's
the father/son game, right?
Not the father/sons game.
A loophole.
only one of us has to go.
Ring, ring.
Hello?
It's the governor.
We're saved!
You're a genius!
Yes, I am. Hey,
good luck at the game.
Remember,
when all Dad's friends...
go up and tousle your hair
and call you "tiger"...
here's what a sincere
smile looks like.
Time out, tooth boy.
Why do I have to go?
Look, Cory, I'd go...
but what if Dad and I started
talking about golf...
talked about how someone
broke his driver...
in the backyard
hittin' rocks with it?
-You wouldn't.
-I would.
oK, fine. I'm gonna go.
But wait. What if Dad
starts joking around...
about how nervous he is
that you're getting...
your driver's license
next year?
I'd have to calm
him down by saying...
"Eric's driven your car
around the block...
"a thousand times,
and nothing's ever happened."
-You wouldn't.
-I would.
-What are you, new?
Look, I'm not going.
Well, I'm not, either.
I guess the only fair way
is to let Dad decide.
-Fine.
May the best excuse win.
-Dad!
[Both shouting at once]
Hey, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Start all over again...
this time in English.
[Both talking at once]
Whoa, whoa. No, try again.
one at a time. You first.
Look, Dad, I can't play in
the softball game tomorrow.
See, Vicki and I have this
really important project...
due next week, and, well,
we've had...
this study date planned
since, like, 1942--
-What subject?
-Science.
You're not in the same class.
We have identical projects
due on the same day, oK?
oh, amazing coincidence.
Isn't it? Look, anyway...
I'm supposed to meet her
at the library tomorrow--
Meet her on Sunday.
The library's closed sunday.
Not anymore.
They changed the hours.
Guys, I got
to tell you something.
Dad, unbelievably,
my left leg...
has to be tested
for radon tomorrow.
I just got a phone call.
Yeah, it's probably nothing...
but I'm the last guy
to endanger my family...
and the testing's free.
The game has been canceled.
And I told them,
"Take the leg off...
"because, darn it, I got
a softball game with my dad!"
They couldn't generate
enough interest.
That stinks.
Yeah, I was psyched.
Ah, don't worry about it.
There'll be other games.
Hey, is the library
really open on Sunday?
How do I know?
Not bad.
So, how was your weekend?
Ah, one of
the all-time greats.
I slept in,
I Watched TV...
I relaxed,
I played video games.
And Sunday, I took it easy.
Hi, Cory.
Hey, look who just
beamed down.
Hi, Topanga.
I missed you
at the game Saturday.
What game?
Your father's grocery store
against my father's bookstore.
Uh, Topanga, in this dimension,
there was no game.
Yes, there was. I played.
Topanga,
that game was canceled.
You wish.
We were killing you...
until your father's
assistant manager...
tried to throw the ball home
from center field...
and sprained his elbow.
The ambulance had to come
and take him away.
There's always an ambulance.
My father told me
that game was called off.
Well, it wasn't.
What's the big deal?
Maybe your dad...
just didn't feel
like playing.
Maybe he didn't feel
like playing alone.
[Music playing]
[Sighs] OK. I'm here. What?
Mom, this is bad.
Look, there was a father/son
softball game on Saturday.
oh, shocker.
You know?
She knows.
I don't get it. Why'd Dad
tell us the game was canceled?
Gee, guys, I'm not sure.
Did you give him any indication
that you didn't want to play?
-No way.
-We were completely cool.
-Completely cool.
-He knew immediately.
-He knows everything.
obviously he picked up
on the fact...
that you didn't want to play...
and he's the one
who let you off the hook.
Worms.
We're worms.
We made our father feel bad.
Mom, can you
get us out of this?
You know,
for old times' sake?
Hmm. Can't.
The fat lady has sung
and gone home.
She's in her kitchen
eating cheesecake.
Come on, Mom.
We made our father feel bad.
Well, he's a big boy.
He'll get over it...
But hopefully you guys learned
something for the next time.
I have. I really have.
Good. Then you
get over it, too.
I can't get over it.
I'll never get over it.
Dad really wanted to play,
and he knew we didn't...
so he dumped the game for us.
It's like
"The Gift of the Magi"...
except we didn't
get him anything.
Are we bad sons, Eric?
Right now we are.
I don't feel so good.
I have appendicitis.
That's not your appendix,
that's your heart.
I have ahearticitis.
[Banging]
Mr. Matthews. Mr. Matthews.
Leonard Spinelli.
I work for your father
down at the grocery store.
We know who you are, Lenny.
We're the ones
that called you.
Yeah, I know.
And it was a rare treat...
but, since you never
called me before...
I thought I'd give
you one last chance...
to make sure
you got the right guy.
Did you get the stuff
we asked you for?
Yes, I did.
Then we got the right guy.
oK, let's see.
Ground chuck.
Hamburger buns.
You may be wondering
how I sprained my elbow.
Lenny, we know you got hurt
at the softball game.
What game?
You're not supposed
to know about the game.
I hurt myself getting out
of a turtleneck that shrunk.
We know about the game, Lenny.
Just don't let Dad know
we know about the game.
Yeah.
oh, boy. oK, let's recap.
Your father says
there was no game...
but knows there was one.
You know there was a game...
but you don't want
your father to know you know.
Well, let me ask you this--
don't you think he knows...
you know he knows you know
you know he knows, you know?
You got to excuse me,
I'm on painkillers.
Root beer.
Pickles and chips.
You know, this is
the first occasion...
I've ever done myself
physical damage...
that I can remember.
Ketchup.
of course, I can remember
many occasions...
when I've done myself
vast emotional damage.
Pimento loaf?
Did We ask for this?
No, but I threw that in
'cause I really love it.
What?
Now we got everything we need...
for that all-guy party
you described.
Lenny--
About that party, Lenny. See--
Vast emotional damage.
We'd be delighted
if you could attend.
Thank you.
Delighted to be here.
I'll go turn off my car.
Is this the best time
you could ever have?
Just cooking burgers
in the backyard...
Dad and his boys...
And his dad's
assistant manager.
Time of my life.
I'd applaud, but I'd pass out.
Salad's done.
Good-looking salad.
Real men need a salad...
they can eat
with their hands.
Yeah, you just pick it up
and dunk it in the dressing.
Ah, no dirty dishes...
No napkins, no utensils...
When we're finished,
we just hose down the porch.
Man meal. End of story.
Boy, you guys know
how to have a good time.
Someday,
when I have a family...
I'm gonna have a good time.
Unless my wife divorces me
and my kids hate me...
because she poisoned them
against me...
and I have to send
my entire weekly paycheck...
to support
the blood-sucking leeches...
while I live
in squalor and despair.
Did I mention
I'm on painkillers?
Root beers all around?
oh, right.
We're having fun now.
You having a good time, Dad?
Hey, great.
What could be better?
Yeah. What could be better?
Yeah.
-Could I see you?
-Yeah.
He hates it.
He doesn't hate it.
He's having a nice time.
Nice isn't
good enough, Eric.
Remember how psyched he was
about the softball game?
That Was the time
he Wanted.
He wanted one lousy
softball game...
and we didn't give it to him.
We gave him dinner.
We gave him dinner...
which he's given us, what,
only every night of our lives.
We thought it would be
such a big deal.
I guess we should've
just given him the game.
Yeah. We should've just
stepped up to the plate...
and said, "l pledge
allegiance to my dad"...
and swung for that
game-winning home run.
Think that would've
been better than tonight?
Hey, you guys.
Come out and get
some pimento loaf.
I just noticed
the expiration date.
oh, yeah.
Much better than tonight.
All right, class, when we were
last in social studies...
We were addressing
the issue of social dissent.
Miss Lawrence?
I've thought over my position,
Mr. Feeny.
And not only do I not want to
say the Pledge of Allegiance...
but I also do not want
to wear shoes.
We who sit behind you object.
Mr. Matthews, you were
a pro-pledger as I recall.
Yeah, I was,
but I thought it over.
oh? You've changed
your position?
No. I haven't,
but I can argue it better now.
Really? Well, then,
the floor is yours.
At first, I thought
we should just say it...
because it was a tradition,
and it's the flag...
but now I think it's dumb...
to do something and not know
why you do it.
And what conclusion
has that led you to?
That if there's something
you care about...
Iike the country you live in
or the father you have...
then allegiance,
which means...
"Noun. Loyalty or devotion
to a government...
"or a group or a person."
Allegiance is something
you should show.
So, then you believe
that you should respect...
the traditions
of that government...
or group or person.
Yeah. I should've.
or teacher?
[Bell rings]
or a teacher.
Why aren't you guys asleep?
We couldn't sleep, Dad.
We got something
on our minds.
Yeah, and it's really
dragging us down.
oh, come on, guys.
Forget it.
You threw me a barbecue.
We're even.
No. We're way past that guilt.
We never found out the score
of the father/son softball game.
oh, well, we got creamed.
18-3.
You let those sandal-wearing,
crystal-packing...
brown rice-eating veg heads
walk all over you?
[Laughs]
Hey, I wasn't even there.
Well, whose fault
is that?
Yours.
-No, it isn't.
-oh, it isn't?
No. Because traditionally...
it's the son's part of the game
to not want to go.
And it's the father's part
of the game to make us go.
You didn't make us go.
You didn't play the game.
You broke
the tradition, Dad.
And I figure
that's why we lost.
You do?
Yeah, but seeing as
we're bucking tradition...
why do we have to wait
a whole year...
to play another
father/son game?
Yeah. How about we challenge
the Unicorn Rainbow Bookstore...
to another game right now?
Well, uh,
I am free next weekend.
-So are we.
-No matter what we're doing.
All right. We got a game.
We got a game.
-oh, Dad...
-Hmm?
-on one condition.
-What?
-Lose the doll.
-Yeah.
Yes! Victory!
Carnivores 36,
Brussels Sprouts 9.
Hut hut!
And here's
the game-winning father now.
Great slide
into home, Dad.
Hey, high five.
All right.
Yeah, that was
a great game.
I had a terrific time.
I can't wait till next year.
Ah, you don't have to.
That's the best part.
Yeah, the bookstore wants to go
best two out of three.
We got a rematch next week.
Hey, that's nice.
Isn't that nice?
Yeah, that's niceമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ