[Music plays]
I have graded last week's
geography examination...
and the highest score
was achieved by--
Minkus. Was it achieved
by Minkus?
Does it go to Minkus?
Minkus, right?
Mr. Minkus.
That's a shock.
Thank you, Mr. Feeny.
Your bonus question
was a real stumper. ow.
Miss owens, excellent.
Mr. Baker, very nice.
Mr. Matthews...
Well, there it is.
A "C"?
But I actually studied
for this test.
Why did I get a "C"?
Let's see. Where to begin.
Well, for one thing,
Mr. Matthews...
this section of the map
is not East Germany.
It's not?
Perhaps you heard
of a little incident...
with the Berlin Wall?
Was that during
baseball season?
There is no
East Germany anymore.
But the textbook says it's
right next to West Germany.
Yes, well, the textbook also
says that Alaska and Hawaii...
will make fine states someday.
Things change, Mr. Matthews.
Unfortunately,
the Board of Education...
doesn't have the funds
to keep up.
Then how am l
supposed to keep up?
Watch the news.
Pay attention in class.
Look at the mimeographs
I give you...
before you turn them
into paper airplanes.
ow.
What good would it do?
They keep
changing geography.
Why can't it be
like all the other subjects?
Math--
2 plus 2 is always 4.
Uh, science--
the Earth always
goes around the Sun.
History--Lincoln always
gets shot in the head.
Lincoln got off easy.
[Theme music plays]
All right, heads up.
In these last few
moments of class...
I want to make
an announcement...
about this year's regional
geography tournament.
As some of you may know,
for the past five years...
I have always fielded
a champion...
and I expect to do
the same this year.
So, based on his outstanding
scholastic achievement...
I have selected
as this year's entrant--
Minkus. Have you
selected Minkus?
Mr. Minkus.
And this year's
first prize will be--
A Mercator projection
pull-down wall map?
No. Uh...
This year's winner
will be bat boy...
at the opening game
of the World Series.
ohh.
Did you hear that?
Yeah. So?
So I'm seeing my
dream come true here.
oh, right. Like Feeny's
going to take you...
to the geography tournament.
You didn't even know...
they tore down
the Berlitz Wall.
[Bell rings]
Uh...about this
geography tournament...
Yeah?
I think you're making
a mistake taking Minkus.
And upon what do you base
that bizarre theory?
Well, what's the most important
ingredient in winning?
Talent.
Skill.
I want you to stop
shaking your head.
The Will to Win.
That's what you need,
that's what I got.
This sudden interest
in geography...
wouldn't have
anything to do...
with this year's World
Series bat boy prize...
would it?
No. No way. Not even.
Are you kidding?
I'm doing this for you.
You're on a 5-year
winning streak...
and I want to bring
the big 6 home to you.
You're sucking up to me.
As hard as I can.
Well, thanks, Mr. Matthews.
Concern like yours
gives me full confidence.
In me?
In Minkus.
It's Minkus.
I'm full of confidence
in Minkus!
Eric, can you babysit...
for your brother
and sister Friday night?
Nope. Sorry.
oh, you misunderstood.
You thought I was
asking you a question.
Mom, Aerosmith's Friday.
oh, you heard about
that concert, too?
Yup. I'm taking
Heather Ralston.
Great.
oh, I'll call a sitter and
we'll all drive together.
What do you mean,
together?
I mean your dad and l
have tickets, too.
Morgan, have you seen
the broccoli?
Broccoli?
Nope.
Mother--and when
I call you that...
I'm referring...
to the generational
chasm between us...
which means you couldn't
possibly be going...
to the same concert as me.
Why not?
Well, you know,
Aerosmith's kind of loud...
for someone your age, Mom.
You should really
be listening to--
Careful.
Aren't Peter, Paul, and Mary
blowing wind somewhere?
Mom, have you met
my good friend Minkus?
It's nice to meet you,
Minkus?
Call my mother.
What?
He's a little nervous,
Mrs. Matthews.
We're gonna take him
upstairs now.
27842--
it's the only Minkus
in the book.
What is this broccoli
doing in here?
It's hiding the liver.
I'm glad you could
come over, Minkus.
Real nice to be here.
Can I go now?
Chill.
I don't understand
what that means.
It means that 1 out of
every 4 people is a nerd.
So when you look
around this room...
and you don't see one,
you're it.
But we can help
you change.
Maybe I like how I am.
You like everyone always
making fun of you?
No.
You like always being the
last one picked for teams?
No.
You like everyone
pulling your underwear...
up your butt
all the time?
It's not so bad.
Minkus, let us help you.
We're here for you, man.
It's early in the year.
You can still
change your image.
What do I do?
The geography tournament--
you don't want to do it.
It'll brand you for life.
But I love geography.
I'm drawn by the adventure
and exoticism of it.
Hey. Perhaps you fellows
would like to join...
the Future Cartographers
of America Club with me.
Let it go, man.
If I don't do the tournament,
will you guys like me?
No.
Then I don't see
what's in it for me.
All right, name your
price, you little creep.
When you guys play
Bombardment...
could you not aim the ball
at my head anymore?
Deal.
What's the point
of playing...
if we can't throw
the ball at his head?
Hi. Who's first?
Dad, you can't go to
the Aerosmith concert.
He's afraid it will
blow out our hearing aids.
I'm just saying
it's unnatural.
I mean can't you guys...
find your own
concert to go to?
I'm sorry
I couldn't get tickets...
for the Neil Sedaka-thon.
Get a clue! We've been
listening to Aerosmith...
since before you were born.
oh, come on,
get out of here.
Don't kill my
first concert, oK?
This isn't your first
Aerosmith concert.
Madison Square Garden, 1978.
We were there,
you were here.
You ate him?
How old are these
Aerosmith guys, anyway...
Iike a million?
Yeah, our age.
Row C-C.
Read 'em and Weep.
That's the third row.
These are amazing.
Yeah. old guys
get good seats.
Maybe we can buy him
decent seats near us...
so he can at least
see the stage.
I don't want to sit
near you guys, oK?
I don't want to be in the
same amphitheater as you.
I don't even want to hear
the same group as you.
I'll go see if there
are any seats left...
for Eric Clapton.
[Door closes]
You want to tell him?
[Bell rings]
Mr. Feeny, I'm afraid I must
tender my resignation...
from the geography tournament.
Mr. Minkus, I'm aware
that the changing...
geopolitical face
of the globe...
offers
a difficult challenge.
I just don't feel that
the geography tournament...
fits in with my new image.
And what, pray tell,
would that image be?
Stuart Minkus, regular guy.
Mr. Minkus, I have
always thought of you...
as exceptional.
Now, why would you suddenly
settle for regular?
Read average,
read mediocre.
Because exceptional people...
get Bombardment balls
thrown at their heads.
And regular guys...
do the throwing.
I see.
And I can't
convince you...
to postpone your
new association...
with the common man until
after the tournament?
No. I'm seizing the day.
Carpe diem. Mr. Feeny.
oh, I'm sorry to hear
that, Mr. Minkus.
You were the only
student I ever had...
who could locate Thrace...
on a map of
the ancient world.
Ah, that's easy.
Just go north
from the Aegean and--
I know what you're doing,
Mr. Feeny...
and it isn't going to--
ain't going to work.
I shall miss you,
Mr. Minkus.
I only wish I knew...
how I was going
to replace you.
Come on, Mr. Feeny.
I'm the only game
in town.
Then, Mr. Matthews,
there is no game.
Uh, Mr. Feeny.
I noticed you've
left the classroom...
and turned east.
Towards Europe,
don't you know?
Come on,
give me a chance.
A chance to what,
Mr. Matthews?
To publicly humiliate me?
No. To win for you.
You've never shown
any interest...
in geography before this.
But I do have
an interest...
in winning the
geography tournament.
I can learn anything
when I'm interested in it.
Are you saying
that you're willing...
to learn something from me?
Yeah.
And if anyone can
teach me, you can.
'Cause that's the kind
of teacher you are.
I'm an empty vessel.
How many times have l
heard you say that?
I've lost count.
But I'm willing
to learn from you.
How many times have
you heard me say that?
Well...I don't believe
I've ever heard those words...
in that order from you.
All right, Mr. Matthews.
I will take you on.
I shall prep you
for the tournament.
I know that your
motives are not pure...
but I hope your
quest for the prize...
will lead you to the
temple of knowledge.
Yeah, yeah.
If it's on the way.
Mm-hmm.
I thought we were
going to the park?
Come on, man, you're
studying too much.
The teachers are
starting to notice.
Yeah, they're calling
you a good student.
They're saying
you have potential.
Wow! The highest
and lowest points...
in the continental
United States...
are only 50 miles apart...
Death Valley
and Mount Whitney.
I find that extraordinary.
Extraordinary?
He's mutating, man.
ow.
Hey, dudes. What's up?
Too Weird for me.
I'm out of here.
Hey, my buds
invited me down...
to the sewer pipes
to break bottles.
Want to come?
Minkus, I'm glad
you're here.
I need to use
your brain.
Sorry, my brain
is no longer in service.
I don't want to lose
this bat boy gig.
In the old days, things
used to be so simple.
You had Russia,
you had Moscow--
one country, one capital.
Now you've got your Latvia,
your Estonia, your Ukraine...
and each one has
its own separate capital.
What were
these people thinking?
Help me, Minkus.
You're on your own, dude.
Every time
I think I'm out...
they try to suck me
back in.
You seem to be holding
your own quite nicely.
Thanks. Last night I watched
House of StyLe on MTV.
What do you think?
I think Western civilization
is in its decline.
I completely agree.
I'm going to watch
Beavis and Butthead now.
So, Mr. Matthews,
how goes the studying?
Great. You know,
I'm really getting into it.
Glad to hear it.
I think you're going to
make an admirable bat boy.
I hope so...
but learning all this stuff
is pretty fun, too.
Did you know that Hawaii...
used to be called
the Sandwich lslands?
Really?
That's fascinating.
We're they named
after somebody?
Yes, the Earl of Sandwich.
Sandwich?
You don't suppose--
yes, he did invent
the sandwich.
Isn't that Weird?
Weird, indeed,
Mr. Matthews.
-The buckeye state?
-ohio.
-The bluegrass state?
-Kentucky.
-Highest mountain in Africa?
-Kilimanjaro.
Elton John.
ours.
-Led Zeppelin.
-oh, please.
-Tina Turner.
-My mother's.
Eric, if it
bothers you so much...
that your mother and I are
going to this concert...
why don't you rebel--
don't go.
oh, yeah. I see
your game here.
You'd love it if I didn't
go to that concert...
wouldn't you?
Nice try, Dad.
Heather and I are going
to that concert.
We're going to be there
64 rows behind you...
breathing down your neck.
Are your shoulders
tense, Mr. Matthews?
Yeah, they're
a little tense.
Then I suggest
you go like this...
You should really relax,
Mr. Feeny.
I got a good feeling
about this.
Your trophy's in the bag...
and I'm gonna be handing out
bats at the Fall Classic.
Here you are, Mr. Bonds.
Pinch hit for you?
Why, it'd be my pleasure.
Moderator:
Contestant 3...
name the indigenous peopLes
of Tierra deL Fuego.
Who are the Yahgans?
It is unnecessary
to phrase your answer...
in the form of a question.
Sorry.
Contestant 4. what
is the primary export...
of the Tuamotus?
Are these guys working
from a different globe?
I believe that
would be copra.
Thank you.
And contestant 5.
to whom do they beLong?
To whom does who belong?
The Tuamotus.
Of what country are
they a possession?
Did you know that Hawaii...
used to be called
the Sandwich lslands...
which were named after
the Earl of Sandwich...
who discovered
peanut butter and jelly?
I'm sorry.
The answer is France.
oh, sure. She gets
a no brainer--"Copra."
Florida is the southernmost
of the United States.
Alaska is the northernmost
Puerto Rico is still
a territory...
so is Guam.
What does a bat boy do?
I don't know.
They hand players bats.
Get it, bat boy?
Well, who would
want to do that?
Yeah. What
a stupid prize.
What ever happened to...
the Mercator projection
pull-down wall map?
oh...
I'm hitting my head.
I'm hitting
the northernmost...
part of my head.
So I try not to look
down at row C-C...
because Heather and I are
having a good time, you know?
But I can't help looking.
Are Mom and Dad sitting
in row C-C?
No, Mom and Dad are
dancing in the aisles.
Come on, Eric, I think your
parents are really cool.
oh, good, I'm the lucky boy
with the cool parents.
Your mom was sitting
on your dad's shoulders.
It Was adorable.
I don't want
adorable parents.
Cory, you want
adorable parents?
Nope. I just want them
to make me lunch...
and pick me up
from camp.
oh, I didn't even tell you
the worst thing they did.
What did they do?
Hey!
They wore that.
Hot concert, huh?
Yeah, hot, Dad.
What's the matter? Didn't
you guys have a good time?
I had a good time.
oh, yeah,
Time of my life!
Come on, Heather.
I'm taking you home.
Eric, what
is the problem?
Well, the problem is
that I've waited all year...
to take Heather
to the Aerosmith concert.
When I finally do...
I should be having
the time of my life.
But I'm not.
You know why?
No, why?
Cory.
What? I'm involved.
This is interesting.
Because my parents
are having my good time.
In better seats.
Why should
our good time...
get in the way
of your good time?
You're my parents!
You're not supposed
to have any fun.
You're supposed to sit here
and wait for me to get home.
And how come I'm home first?
We had backstage passes.
All right, that's it.
Cory, move over.
I'm sitting next to you
in the loser's couch.
You lost that
geography thing...
and I lost my music,
my parents...
my entire generation.
I studied geography
for the last 300 hours...
and I have nothing
to show for it.
I had to wait
in line all night...
to get those tickets.
The only thing I have
to show for it is...
Sonny and Cher.
Eric, I'm sorry, and I know
it's tough to hear this...
but your mother and l
are at an awkward age.
We're parents,
but we're not dead yet.
Fine. Glad somebody
had a good time.
Come on, Heather.
I'm taking you home.
Eric, stop right there.
Sit back in that couch,
both of you.
Join me on the couch,
Heather?
Cory, upstairs.
Why? I'm not remotely tired.
Cory.
But suddenly, I'm
overcome with fatigue.
Come on, sweetie.
But I want to watch
Eric get yelled at.
Lots of opportunities
for that.
You know, Dad, it really
wouldn't be too cool...
to start yelling at me
in front of my girlfriend.
You know,
when I was your age...
I had a father
like the one you want.
But What I Wanted...
was a father like
the one you got.
Live With it.
Did my parents just
leave us alone...together?
Yeah, I think
they just did.
I'm the lucky boy
with the cool parents.
Not that cool!
[Bell rings]
Mr. Minkus...
I see you've abandoned
your MTV look.
Well, nothing against
Cindy Crawford...
but I'm more of a
Connie Chung kind of guy.
Well, sometimes a man
doesn't know himself...
until he's walked a mile...
in another man's
humungous pants.
Hey, Minkus.
Who owns the Tuamotus?
France.
oh.
He would've brought home
the big 6, wouldn't he?
Very likely.
Well, I want you to know
that I tried my hardest.
Did you?
Do you really feel
you gave it your best...
that you studied...
as hard as
you possibly could?
Yeah, I do.
You know, Mr. Matthews, many
1 5th century explorers...
believed that geography
meant taking...
their little boat
as far as it could go...
before it fell
off the earth.
You have pushed yourself
to your farthest latitudes.
And not only did you not
topple over the edge...
but, I believe, together...
we have charted
new territory.
What's this?
That is this week's
geography exam.
I got an "A"?
Yes, it's an "A."
Congratulations,
Mr. Matthews.
We won.
Sports announcer:
There are 2 outs...
and Barry Bonds
steps up to the pLate.
The pitcher
winds up and--
Second announcer: Wait.
wait. wait a minute. Ed.
It Looks Like the bat boy is
running out onto the fieLd!
She seems to be
carrying a banner...
and she's hoLding
it up. John.
Gosh. Ed. what's it say?
It says. "Get France
out of the Tuamotus. "
Where are
the Tuamotus. Ed?
WeLL. I guess they're
in France. John.
Hey. you know I aLways
thought the Tuamotus...
were the indigenous peopLes
of Tierra deL Fuego.
Oh. no. John.
Those are the Yahgansമഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ