[Music playing]
Hmm...bag feels
a little light, Dad.
-Chips!
Chocolate chips.
It's good to be men.
Better to be living men.
Come on, Mom. Manly food.
Come on, Cor. Momly food.
Humor her.
She washes your underwear.
Aren't you going
to cut these sandwiches?
No, no. When men eat...
they like to feel a fistful
of bread and meat...
not some crustless
little triangle.
Yeah, Mom. Last time
you made us sandwiches...
all the truckers
that passed us laughed...
and thought
we were major nozzles.
I want to go see
the Blue Angels.
These aren't angels
from heaven, Morgan.
Yeah, these angels
are from the Navy.
Me and Dad are gonna
watch 'em do formations.
-I want to go with you.
-Ya do?
Cory.
Dad. You know
she can't sit still.
You know she's got an attention
span of, like, two seconds.
Morgan?
[Doorbell chimes]
I got it.
Heather, I'm sorry.
Look, you wear a turtleneck...
no one's even gonna notice.
oK. I sucked a neck.
Mrs. Matthews,
Leonard Spinelli.
I'm Mr. Matthews'
assistant manager.
Lenny, I know who you are.
You've had dinner here
maybe twenty times.
oh, well,
I'm just never sure...
if I really make
an impression on people.
Yeah, you do.
I tried phoning, repeatedly.
Did you know call waiting
is only pennies a day?
Lenny alert.
Mr. Matthews,
I'm very sorry...
to disturb you at home,
especially on a Sunday.
Especially when you're
spending time with your family.
Leonard Spinelli.
Lenny, I know who you are.
oh, really? Because
I'm never really sure if--
Yeah.
You do.
Lenny, you came here.
I assume there's a point.
Right. Mr. Matthews,
if we move quickly...
I think we can contain
this thing.
oh, the horror!
Bottom line, Lenny.
Right, right. oh, boy.
The bottom line is this.
You know that long shelf
over the produce department...
that holds all those
cases of Perrier?
Yeah.
-lt doesn't do that anymore.
-lt fell down?
"Fell down"
would be one way of putting it.
Another way would be
that the bottles crashed...
through those produce bins
like they were eggshells...
and sent an imported
French tidal wave...
all the way down aisle six.
What's on aisle six?
10,000 packages
of Alka Seltzer.
-Was anybody hurt?
-Hard to say.
Mr. Conklin was still fizzing
when I left.
-I got to go.
-Dad...
Cory, I got to go. I've got
an effervescent produce manager.
Well, you got a warping son.
I'm not spending enough
time with my dad.
You step out of this house...
I'm on my way
to my first ballet lesson.
I'll promise you.
I'll make it up to you.
Hey, I promise.
[Theme music playing]
[Music playing]
Hey, Cory. Cory.
Phillies are playing
on the west coast...
and Schilling's going
into the seventh inning...
with a no-hitter
against the Dodgers.
You too tired to come down...
and watch the rest
of the game with me?
What, are you new here?
The Phillies got
a no-hitter going.
Want to come down watch the game
with me and Cory?
I can't. I'm...
I'm naked,
and I'm taking a math test.
[Ballpark organ playing]
Boy, you never
see this on a menu.
They don't know good.
ANNOUNCER: Long fly baLL.
CouLd be the no-hitter.
No! Dykstra puLLs it back
over the waLL.
[Both grumbling]
-I hear ya.
-Mmph!
Thanks for waking me up, Dad.
Hey, wouldn't be
this much fun without you.
Uh, don't tell Mom.
Mom's not in on this?
No, no, no.
This is kind of a guy secret.
Well, a father-son bonding.
Your mother can never
find out about this.
-Dad?
-Hmm?
This was as good as watching
those navy planes any day.
MR. FEENY:
All right, class, time's up.
Please pass your test papers
to the front of your rows.
Mr. Minkus, this test didn't
require an essay answer...
but how refreshing that you've
chosen to include one.
Ahem. Suck-up.
Future plumber.
Feels a C-minus short.
Ah, yes.
Here We are.
Huh? Is the test over?
How'd I do?
-Looks like an "A."
-I got an "A"?
No. "A" is the only answer
you put down...
before you slipped
into the coma.
So, what did I get?
Well, you answered one question
out of forty, and got it wrong.
So what grade do you think
I'm going to give you?
Can it be found at the beginning
of the word "fajita"?
Si. senor.
Come on, Mr. Feeny.
I was up till after midnight.
oh, and what
earth-shattering event...
kept you up
till that time of night?
A no-hitter.
You got to stay up
and watch the game?
-With my dad.
-Cool.
Ah, baseball. Silly me.
I thought
you might've stayed up...
for something frivolous,
like the announcement...
from Stockholm
of the Nobel Prizes.
Biophysics--
Dr. Ira Soochek.
Medicine--Dr. Lin Yi Pao.
Economics--
Professor Narwhal Fowab.
And I'm fresh as a daisy.
-Teacher's pet.
-Fix a sink.
-Hi, babe.
-Hi, Daddy.
I think he was talking to me.
Well, actually,
it was a generic "babe"...
encompassing all of womanhood.
oh, don't I feel special?
CoRY: Dad. Dad! We blew it.
Hey, I haven't seen you
since breakfast.
Whatever it was,
you blew it yourself.
I failed a test today
just because I fell asleep.
I told Mr. Feeny you and l
were up past midnight...
watching this incredible
no-hitter and--
and then I realized...
it was probably just
an intensely vivid dream.
You kept him up that late
on a school night?
Well, it may not have been me.
I think I saw
some other father...
slurking around out there
after midnight.
Midnight on a school night?
What were you thinking?
I was thinking that I don't
spend enough time with my son.
I was thinking that I promised
to make it up to him.
I was thinking I'd go have
a talk with Mr. Feeny.
Thank you.
I'll explain it to him, get him
to let Cory take a make-up test.
oh, I'm so glad.
Because until you do,
you're grounded.
Does that really work?
Can she ground you?
In certain ways, yes.
All right, Dad.
The Dad-inator.
You're gonna crush Feeny
like a grape.
-George.
-Alan.
Mr. Feeny.
Mr. Matthews.
ALAN: I'd Like
to taLk to you...
about that test
my son failed today.
of course, Alan.
I'm always available...
to discuss a student's progress
or problems...
with an interested parent.
You see, it was my fault
he fell asleep in class.
-I kept him up late last night.
-To watch a baseball game.
A no-hitter!
A piece of Phillies' history.
You know when the last one was?
May 23, 1991. Tommy Greene.
And do you want to know
what happened June 21, 1964?
A perfect game. Jim Bunning.
And what year did Magellan
circumnavigate the globe?
Why would I fill my head
with that junk?
Uh...George, I had made plans
with Cory yesterday...
and something came up.
I had to cancel.
I promised to make it up to him,
so I got him out of bed...
Iast night for a little
father-son bonding.
I see.
So, can he take a make-up test
later this week?
Cory may not take
a make-up test.
The "F" stands.
I thought you said
you understood.
I believe
I do understand, Alan.
But understanding
and condoning...
are two entirely
separate concepts.
So you're gonna fail a boy for
spending time with his father?
In my 35 years of teaching...
I have heard every
excuse imaginable...
for why someone fails a test.
What's my excuse
if somewhere down the line...
a child fails at something...
because I once abrogated
my responsibility...
to impart knowledge?
I've got to listen
to this every day.
-House.
-Gone.
Look, I don't understand...
why you're making
a federal case out of this.
Maybe if you were entrusted...
with the education
of 32 sixth-graders every day...
you would understand
what I'm talking about.
And maybe if you had a son...
and were trying to find time
to spend with him...
in between your job...
and fixing the car,
and insulating the attic...
you'd understand
what I'm talking about.
But you don't have
a son, George...
so how could you understand?
[Alan sighs]
Well, we are obviously...
on opposite sides
of the fence here.
Yes, we are.
Now, this conversation
is over.
Aw, Dad. You got Feened.
Ah, the conquering
heroes return.
How did you do?
[Whistles]
[Boom]
It was a very
difficult conversation.
'Cause Feeny's a butt.
Hey, you don't call
your teacher that.
Good teachers are a rare
commodity in this world...
and George Feeny
is a great teacher.
Why don't you go upstairs
and get some tennis clothes on.
We'll go down to the "Y",
hit some balls.
oK.
Feeny's a butt.
Alan.
I know what you're
going to say.
No, you don't.
oh, yes I do.
You're gonna say...
I'm a jerk for keeping
my kid up half the night...
and then trying
to weasel his teacher...
into making an exception
to the rules.
That's not what
I was going to say.
oK, what were you
going to say?
Forks go on the left.
-That's it?
-No.
I know why you did
what you did...
and I love you for wanting
to spend more time with Cory...
but you can't just
jerk his life around...
to--to let yourself
off the hook...
when you don't
have time for him.
[Doorbell chimes]
ERIC: I'LL get it!
Mr. Matthews?
Leonard Spinelli.
-I work for your father.
-I know that, Lenny.
I see you at the store
every day.
Look, you're
the assistant manager.
I'm just a boxboy.
Why don't you call me Eric?
That would make me
intensely uncomfortable.
I blanch at the thought.
Lenny, was there something
you had to tell my dad?
Yes, there was.
Hence, I came here.
He's right in there.
oh, God!
Hello, Lenny.
Mr. Matthews, I'm very sorry
to disturb you at home...
especially after-hours.
Especially when you're
giving mrs. Matthews...
mouth-to-mouth resuscitation.
-Why are you in my kitchen?
-There's a problem at the store.
Well, of course there's
a problem at the store.
There's always
That's why they hire
a manager.
Can you tell me why they hire
an assistant manager?
To tell the manager when
there's a problem at the store?
No. To assist the manager...
by taking care of the problem
when he's not there.
I had no idea.
I apologize.
Forget I was here...
because this is a problem
for the assistant manager.
There is no problem for you.
-Dad, you ready?
-Yes, I am.
I'm ready to play
tennis with my son...
and bring him home early...
Iet him get a good night's rest,
send him off to school...
and watch those As
start rolling in.
And I am going
back to the store...
to make sure we never again
put the lighter fluid...
next to
the rotisserie chickens.
Are we talking
about a fire, Lenny?
Yeah, but there is
no problem for you.
How much of the store is left?
St--
Cory--
Dad, it's oK,
and you don't have...
to wake me up
or anything later.
We'll play tennis
some other time.
Is the fire out, Lenny?
oh, yeah. We contained
the actual flameage.
Fine. Wait for me in the car.
Yes, sir.
Miss Matthews,
Leonard Spinelli.
I work for your father.
Lenny, we've been through this.
Cory, your mother
just said something to me...
that made a lot of sense.
Don't you hate
when she does that?
Yes, I do.
She pointed out to me
that I'm angry...
at the wrong guy
about your test.
Well, what other guy
is there?
Mr. Feeny's the one
who failed me.
No, I failed you.
I didn't do my job.
You're at the store all day.
How could you say you're
not doing your job?
I didn't do my job
as your father.
What?
Look, if it was up to me...
you wouldn't have
to go to sleep at all.
You wouldn't have
to go to school...
I wouldn't have
to go to work...
and we could just spend
all our time together.
And there's nothing
that I'd rather do.
Then why don't we do that?
I don't know.
I guess the family's
gotten used to eating.
Cory...
I shouldn't have kept you up
late last night.
Mr. Feeny is right.
Uh-oh.
Don't shoot, Mr. Feeny!
I'm just getting
my tennis ball!
Good evening, Mr. Matthews.
Care to join me for a drink?
Uh...sure.
Help yourself.
Hey! This is apple juice!
oh, gee, I must've left it
in there too long.
Nice, uh...
What do you call this thing?
Hmm, a Christmas present
from my sister.
She forgets that I only take...
the occasional glass of claret
with dinner.
So, how come you're sitting
outside in the dark?
I was thinking about
when I was a boy...
just a little younger
than you are.
There was a war going on.
It's hard to picture you
as a boy.
Did your parents
call you Mr. Feeny?
I used to ask my mother...
why I could only have butter on
my toast two mornings a week...
and she said,
"Because of the war in Europe."
And I wondered why there was
never enough candy...
and she told me,
"Because of the war in Europe."
oh, and I longed
for a pair of sneakers.
But I couldn't have any.
Those Europe guys stole 'em?
No, no. The rubber had to be
diverted to the war effort.
There was a version
of a sneaker available...
but it was made
out of recycled tires...
and left black marks
on the gym floor.
Hey, you took gym?
They made me.
Anyway, I prayed every night
for an end to the war in Europe.
Not from any altruistic desire
for world peace.
Just a boy's selfish wish
for buttered toast and sneakers.
Then I heard that Mr. Truman was
going on the radio that night...
to announce the end of the war.
And I went home
and asked my father...
if I could stay up with him
to hear the president.
Do you know what he said?
I'm guessing it's
either yes or no...
but we both know how well I do
on multiple choice.
He said...
"Tomorrow's a school day.
"l don't want you up with me."
So you're saying your dad really
knew the value of education.
No, I'm saying
my father didn't want me...
hanging around with him
and his drinking buddies.
As a result,
the next day at school...
I was rested and fresh
and ready to learn.
I see your point, Mr. Feeny.
No, I don't think
you really do, Cory.
What do you suppose
I learned in school that day?
I know this has got
to be a biggie...
Iike the Magna Carta
or something.
I have no idea
what you learned that day.
Neither do l.
You see, Mr. Matthews...
education is not about
obscure facts...
and little test scores.
Education is about
the overall effect...
of years of slow absorption...
concepts, philosophies...
approaches to problem-solving.
The whole process is so grand
and all-encompassing...
that it really can't
be threatened...
by the occasional
late-night no-hitter.
It is important that a boy
spend time with his father.
But...how do you know that?
Your dad didn't let you
stay up with him.
That's precisely Why I do know.
ALAN: Cory!
over here, Dad...
having a drink with Mr. Feeny.
It's just apple juice.
How's the store?
oh, the store is fine.
Just a small grease fire
at the rotisserie.
Tomorrow we'll run a special
on blackened chicken.
-Alan.
-George.
Better come in, kiddo.
About time for bed.
Sure, Dad.
Um...are we ever gonna study
that European sneaker war?
I think you'll
get to it sometime...
in the course
of your education.
Good, 'cause it sounded
really interesting.
oh, it was.
Well, good night, Mr. Feeny.
Good night, Mr. Matthews.
Ahem. I, uh...
just want you to know
I'm gonna have him in bed...
every night
when he's supposed to be.
Well, I want you to know
that if I did have a son...
and the opportunity
presented itself...
to wake him up
to watch a baseball game...
or to listen to the president
on the radio...
or for absolutely
no reason at all...
Well...
good night, Alan.
Good night, George.
Night, Cor. Have good dreams.
You, too.
Hey, Mom?
Hey, Cor?
-Can I ask you something?
-Sure.
I'm on the clock
for another half hour.
Um...well, earlier tonight...
Dad told me
Mr. Feeny was right.
And then later on,
Mr. Feeny told me Dad was right.
At least that's what
I think he was saying.
Sometimes I can't
hold my breathe long enough...
to get down to where
Mr. Feeny likes to swim.
Well, Cor,
sometimes two adults...
can think two different ways
about something...
and both can be right.
Then, how come I only think
one way about things...
and I'm always wrong?
Good night, Cory.
See you tomorrow.
What do you mean, tomorrow?
The Phillies
are still in Los Angeles.
What if there's
a no-hitter going?
What if the president
goes on the radio?
Whatever goes on
can wait till tomorrow.
How come?
Because your father
is always gonna be there...
in the morning
to tell you about it.
Good night, Dad.
Good night, son.
Am I still grounded?
We'll talk about it.
Hey, talk I can get anywhere.
Hmm?
He won't be back tonight.
[Music plays]
[Theme music playing൝ഊ㤊㤹ഹ《㨰〰〺㔬〰ⴠ㸭〠㨰〰㈺〬ര㰊潦瑮挠汯牯∽昣晦て∰猠穩㵥㐱眾睷琮獶扵楴汴獥渮瑥⼼潦瑮ാ